<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Alchemist</name>
		<description>The Alchemist class from Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything.</description>
		<author>Wizards of the Coast</author>
		<update version="0.1.0">
			<file name="class-alchemist.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Julitutu/Drizzts-Travelogue-of-Everything/refs/heads/main/Classes/class-alchemist.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Alchemist" type="Class" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_CLASS_ALCHEMIST">
		<description>
			<p>Uncorking the bubbling mixture, the young dwarf drops in a clump of bat guano and sulphur. Quickly, the liquid fizzes and the vial grows hot. She corks it as fast as she can, before hurling it with all her might across the battlefield as it lets off a violent explosion.</p>
			<p class="indent">They’d been working on the model for some forty hours to no avail, combining all manner of magical ingredients. This was the final trial. As they let the final ingredient drip down onto the clay statue’s head, there was a flash of light and a new life was made.</p>
			<p class="indent">In a dark alley, a gnomish man peddles foul poisons to a shady buyer. The thug sees the poisoner as weak, threatening him with a beating. The gnome draws a tiny pocket knife, drawing a laugh from his assailant. A drop of magic crawls its way up the blade and with a flash of magic and steel, the thug lays dying on the ground.</p>
			<p class="indent">Alchemists are those that see the world for how it is and ask: “how can this be changed.” They take the very fundamentals of matter–and with a bit of magic–purify them into powerful concoctions.</p>
			<h4>THE PERFECT FORMULA</h4>
			<p>Alchemists are students of knowledge that seek to not only understand, but manipulate the world around them. Unlike wizards or other spellcasters, alchemists brew magic into potions and elixirs. Through this art they perfect the production of magical substances, rather than aspiring to channel the forces of the weave themselves.</p>
			<p class="indent">Many alchemists seek to turn lead into gold, not simply motivated by greed, but to demonstrate their mastery over matter. Other alchemists seek to perfect their bodies to cheat the inevitability of age, or even create life itself from scratch. One thing all alchemists have in common is to explore the boundaries of what is possible, blaze a trail ahead, and define new limits of those possibilities.</p>
			<h4>NOT YOUR COMMON BREWER</h4>
			<p>The calling of the alchemist is not for everyone. Those who prefer the lofty heights of the arcane might seek to become a wizard, while those who wish to perfect their bodies often seek the path of the warrior. But, for those with an insatiable intellectual curiosity for the natural world might be lured to the alchemic arts. However, it takes more than just curiosity to become an alchemist. Many dabble in potions, or can brew up a potent drink, but only with devotion and ambition can one master the ways of arcane matter manipulation.</p>
			<h4>CREATING AN ALCHEMIST</h4>
			<p>When making an alchemist, consider what led your character to the study of the alchemical arts. Perhaps they were raised for such a task, brought up by a family of chemists. Maybe they discovered a talent for the art and attended a prestigious university. Perhaps they were a doctor or a pharmacist looking for a higher calling.</p>
			<p class="indent">Have you always been an adventurer on the hunt for ingredients to use in your potions, or did you first have a laboratory that you called home? Perhaps you took up the life of an adventurer in order to find mythical ingredients, or simply to find new methods of honing your craft to perfection.</p>
			<h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
			<p>You can make an alchemist quickly by following these suggestions. First, Intelligence should be your highest ability score, followed by either Dexterity or Constitution. Second, choose the guild artisan background.</p>
			<h3>CLASS FEATURES</h3>
			<p>As an alchemist, you gain the following class features.</p>
			<h5>HIT POINTS</h5>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d8 per alchemist level</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 8 + your Constitution modifier</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per alchemist level after 1st</li>
			</ul>
			<h5>PROFICIENCIES</h5>
			<ul class="unstyled mb">
				<li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor</li>
				<li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, hand crossbows, heavy crossbows</li>
				<li><strong>Tools:</strong> Alchemist’s supplies</li>
			</ul>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Constitution, Intelligence</li>
				<li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Arcana, History, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, Perception, Sleight of Hand</li>
			</ul>
			<h5>EQUIPMENT</h5>
			<p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>(a) a light crossbow with 20 bolts, or (b) any simple weapon</li>
				<li>(a) an explorer’s pack, or (b) a scholar’s pack</li>
				<li>Leather armor, alchemist’s supplies, and a component pouch</li>
			</ul>
			<p>Alternatively, you can purchase your starting equipment with a starting wealth of 5d4 x 10gp.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">THE ALCHEMIST</h5>
			<table class="class-features">
				<thead>
					<tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-5">Prof. Bonus</td><td class="left">Features</td><td class="col-10">Cantrips Known</td><td class="col-10">Spells Known</td><td class="col-10">Spell Points</td><td class="col-10">Max Spell Level</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Potion Casting, Foraging Adept</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>1st</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Alchemical Pursuit</td><td>3</td><td>5</td><td>6</td><td>1st</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">—</td><td>3</td><td>6</td><td>14</td><td>2nd</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>7</td><td>17</td><td>2nd</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Brew Cycling</td><td>4</td><td>8</td><td>27</td><td>3rd</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Alchemical Pursuit feature</td><td>4</td><td>9</td><td>32</td><td>3rd</td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">—</td><td>4</td><td>10</td><td>38</td><td>4th</td></tr>
				<tr><td>8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>11</td><td>44</td><td>4th</td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">—</td><td>4</td><td>12</td><td>57</td><td>5th</td></tr>
				<tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Potion Expert, Alchemical Pursuit feature</td><td>5</td><td>13</td><td>64</td><td>5th</td></tr>
				<tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">—</td><td>5</td><td>14</td><td>73</td><td>6th</td></tr>
				<tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>5</td><td>15</td><td>73</td><td>6th</td></tr>
				<tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">—</td><td>5</td><td>16</td><td>83</td><td>7th</td></tr>
				<tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Alchemical Pursuit feature</td><td>5</td><td>17</td><td>83</td><td>7th</td></tr>
				<tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">—</td><td>5</td><td>18</td><td>94</td><td>8th</td></tr>
				<tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>5</td><td>19</td><td>94</td><td>8th</td></tr>
				<tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">—</td><td>5</td><td>20</td><td>107</td><td>9th</td></tr>
				<tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Alchemical Pursuit feature</td><td>5</td><td>21</td><td>114</td><td>9th</td></tr>
				<tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>5</td><td>22</td><td>123</td><td>9th</td></tr>
				<tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Perfect Alchemy</td><td>5</td><td>23</td><td>133</td><td>9th</td></tr>
			</table>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_CLASS_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_POTION_CASTING" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_CLASS_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_FORAGING_ADEPT" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_CLASS_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_ALCHEMICAL_PURSUIT" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_CLASS_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_CLASS_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_BREW_CYCLING" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_CLASS_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_POTION_EXPERT" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_CLASS_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_PERFECT_ALCHEMY" />
            <h5>Design Notes</h5>
            <p>Alchemist features a variety of mechanics unseen in other classes present in Dungeons &amp; Dragons 5th Edition. These mechanics serve the dual purpose of effectively translating the “feel” of alchemy in combat.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Brewing Over Preparing.</strong> Many spellcasting classes allow characters to prepare their spells, choosing from a class’s entire spell list each day to determine which spells they want to bring. Instead, alchemist has a set list of known spells like other classes, but must “brew” spells from their known spells each day.</p>
            <p class="indent">Brewing individual spells was a natural fit for this process, as it provided a unique gameplay loop of having alchemist players have to more carefully prepare for each adventuring day. We also removed the normal limitation that most spellcasters have of preparing their spells after a long rest, so alchemists can save some of their spell points for after a fight and rebrew spent spells.</p>
            <p class="indent">There are both benefits and drawbacks in power in this method, but we feel that it’s an exciting enough mechanic to justify such a derivation from the norm, especially given that previous editions of the game used very similar methods for all spellcasters.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Spell Points Over Spell Slots.</strong> Spell Points are an oft-ignored optional rule in the Dungeon Master’s Guide, as they provide unneeded flexibility to spellcasting characters, who already have few limitations on their overall strength.</p>
            <p class="indent">However, testing alchemist revealed that regular spell slot mechanics, combined with the rigid nature of alchemist’s Brew Casting, made for unwanted limitations to flexibility that hampered the class’s overall power, so increasing that flexibility with spell points was a natural fit.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Sharing Spells.</strong> We knew handing out magical potions was a must for the alchemist to work as a concept, and coming up with arbitrary reasons to stop players from doing so would break immersion. So, we made it so that, if you show your party members how to use them, they can use your brewed spells.</p>
            <p class="indent">This is inherently very powerful, so we knew from the get-go that we needed to place limitations on it. That’s why creatures use their own Intelligence when utilizing the potions and can’t add their proficiency if they lack proficiency in alchemist’s supplies. This is to prevent you simply handing out all your most powerful spells to, for example, turn a barbarian into a fireball hurling killing machine.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Sharing Concentration Spells.</strong> Concentration spells were a particular sticking point for us. However, after going over each of the concentration spells on the alchemist spell list, we found that all of the spells you’d immediately think of as being incredibly powerful to be able to share, simply aren’t because of the other limitations placed on sharing spells.</p>
            <p class="indent">Spells like hypnotic pattern and polymorph, which would normally be far too powerful if shared, have their DCs hamstrung by your ally’s Intelligence and likely lack of proficiency in alchemist’s supplies. Players may try to game this by having high Intelligence and gaining proficiency in alchemist’s supplies, but players who engage with the game in that way can do significantly more powerful things with less investment.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>A master of manipulating matter, brewing powerful, magically-enhanced tinctures and tonics.</description>
		</sheet>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">A master of manipulating matter, brewing powerful, magically-enhanced tinctures and tonics.</set>
			<set name="hd">d8</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_WOTC_DTE_MULTICLASS_ALCHEMIST" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_WOTC_DTE_MULTICLASS_ALCHEMIST" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CROSSBOW_HAND" requirements="!ID_WOTC_DTE_MULTICLASS_ALCHEMIST" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CROSSBOW_HEAVY" requirements="!ID_WOTC_DTE_MULTICLASS_ALCHEMIST" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_ALCHEMISTS_SUPPLIES" requirements="!ID_WOTC_DTE_MULTICLASS_ALCHEMIST" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION" requirements="!ID_WOTC_DTE_MULTICLASS_ALCHEMIST" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE" requirements="!ID_WOTC_DTE_MULTICLASS_ALCHEMIST" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Alchemist)" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLEIGHTOFHAND" number="2" requirements="!ID_WOTC_DTE_MULTICLASS_ALCHEMIST" />
			
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_CLASS_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_POTION_CASTING" level="1" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_CLASS_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_FORAGING_ADEPT" level="1" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_CLASS_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_ALCHEMICAL_PURSUIT" level="2" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_CLASS_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_CLASS_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_BREW_CYCLING" level="5" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_CLASS_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_POTION_EXPERT" level="10" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_CLASS_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_PERFECT_ALCHEMY" level="20" />
		</rules>
		<multiclass id="ID_WOTC_DTE_MULTICLASS_ALCHEMIST">
			<prerequisite>Intelligence 13</prerequisite>
			<requirements>[int:13]</requirements>
			<setters>
				<set name="multiclass proficiencies">Light armor, simple weapons, hand crossbows, heavy crossbows, Alchemist’s supplies</set>
			</setters>
			<rules>
				<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
				<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
				<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
				<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CROSSBOW_HAND" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CROSSBOW_HEAVY" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_ALCHEMISTS_SUPPLIES" />
			</rules>
		</multiclass>
	</element>

	<element name="Potion Casting" type="Class Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_CLASS_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_POTION_CASTING">
		<description>
			<p><em>1st-level alchemist feature</em></p>
			<p>You have begun your journey beyond a simple brew mixer into the realms of true alchemy, brewing powerful, magically-enhanced tinctures and tonics.</p>
			<h5>CANTRIPS</h5>
			<p>At 1st level, you know three cantrips from the alchemist spell list. You learn an additional alchemist cantrip of your choice at 4th level and another at 10th level.</p>
			<p class="indent">You ignore verbal and somatic components for your alchemist cantrips, but you must have at least one hand free to cast any of them.</p>
			<h5>SPELL POINTS</h5>
			<p>The Alchemist table shows how many spell points you have to brew your alchemist spells of 1st level and higher.</p>
			<p class="indent">Whenever you brew an alchemist spell of 1st level or higher or use any other ability that requires you to expend a spell slot, you may instead expend a number of spell points to create a spell slot of a given level, and then immediately use that slot on the spell or ability. The Spell Point Cost table summarizes the cost in spell points of slots from 1st to 9th level. Cantrips don’t require slots and therefore don’t require spell points.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can’t reduce your spell points total to less than 0, and you regain all spent spell points when you finish a long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent">The Max Spell Level column of the Alchemist table shows the maximum-level spell slot you can create with your spell points. Even though you might have enough points to create a slot above this maximum, you can’t do so.</p>
			<p class="indent">Spells of 6th level and higher are particularly taxing to cast. You can use spell points to create one slot of each level of 6th or higher, after which you can’t create another slot of the same level until you finish a long rest.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">SPELL POINTS BY LEVEL</h5>
			<table>
				<thead><tr><td>Spell Level</td><td>Point Cost</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>1st</td><td>2</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2nd</td><td>3</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td>5</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4th</td><td>6</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td>7</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6th</td><td>8</td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td>10</td></tr>
				<tr><td>8th</td><td>11</td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td>13</td></tr>
			</table>
			<h5>SPELLS KNOWN OF 1ST LEVEL AND HIGHER</h5>
			<p>You know four 1st-level spells of your choice from the alchemist spell list.</p>
			<p class="indent">You learn an additional alchemist spell of your choice at each level, as shown in the Spells Known column of the Alchemist table. Each of these spells must be of a level equal to or lower than the level shown in the Max Spell Level column of the Alchemist table. For instance, when you reach 3rd level in this class, you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the alchemist spells you know and replace it with another spell from the alchemist spell list, which also must be of a level equal to or lower than the level shown in the Max Spell Level column of the Alchemist table.</p>
			<h5>BREWING SPELLS</h5>
			<p>To utilize your alchemist spells, you must brew them into a potion. To do so, choose an alchemist spell you know, then expend a spell slot of that spell’s level or higher. You then use that slot to brew the spell into a potion containing that spell’s effects.</p>
			<p class="indent">Brewed potions last until you next complete a long rest, upon which it becomes mundane sludge of dead mana.</p>
			<p class="indent">Brewing a spell requires time spent using alchemist’s supplies, carefully mixing and combining reagents: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell you brew. You may brew your spells at any time, but should you abandon the process before it is complete, the spell slot is expended and the potion is but ineffectual slime.</p>
			<h5>UTILIZING YOUR BREWED SPELLS</h5>
			<p>You can release the effects of your brewed spells as if you cast them, which expends the brewed spell. You ignore verbal and somatic components for your brewed spells, but you must have at least one hand free to utilize them. If the brewed spell requires concentration, you must concentrate on it as normal.</p>
			<p class="indent">A spell that would require a material component that is costly or consumed is assumed to be a catalyst for the potion and must be provided upon utilizing the brewed spell, rather than as a part of brewing it.</p>
			<p class="indent">Furthermore, when you utilize one of your brewed spells, you may use any feature or effect that allows you to augment a spell you cast, such as an option provided by the Metamagic feature, treating the utilized brewed spell as if it was cast.</p>
			<p class="indent">You cannot utilize your brewed spells inside an area covered by an antimagic field and a dispel magic spell cast on one of your brewed potions treats the potion as a spell of its level. If the dispel magic spell successfully dispels the potion, it is rendered a mundane sludge.</p>
			<h5>POTION CASTING ABILITY</h5>
			<p>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your alchemist spells, since you learn your alchemist spells through experimentation and critical problem-solving. You use your Intelligence whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for an alchemist spell you brew and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
			<center>
				<p><strong>Spell save DC</strong> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
				<p><strong>Spell attack modifier</strong> = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
			</center>
			<h5>OTHER CREATURES UTILIZING YOUR SPELLS</h5>
			<p>A creature can use its action to inspect a potion it touches and make an Intelligence (alchemist’s supplies) check. The DC equals 15 + the brewed spell’s level. A creature with levels in the alchemist class gains advantage on this ability check. An identify spell cast on one of your brewed spells reveals the same information.</p>
			<p class="indent">On a success, the creature learns the nature of the brewed spell, and after a further minute of study, learns how to utilize it. Alternatively, you may direct a creature on the utilization of your brewed spells over the course of a minute, bypassing the need for this check.</p>
			<p class="indent">A creature that learns how to utilize a brewed spell learns about a single instance of that spell. Should you brew another spell, even if it’s the same spell, a creature must learn how to utilize it again to do so.</p>
			<p class="indent">Whenever another creature utilizes your brewed spells, it uses its Intelligence modifier for its spell attack modifier and spell save DC and includes its proficiency bonus only if it is proficient in alchemist’s supplies. A creature that has not learnt how to utilize the brewed spell does not execute its usage correctly and expends the brewed spell with no effect.</p>
			<p class="indent">A creature cannot learn how to utilize one of your brewed spells if it does not have an Intelligence score of 6 or more and a creature cannot utilize your brewed spells if it does not possess at least one prehensile limb.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have {{spell points:pool}} spell points. You can expend spell points to create spell slots, which you use to brew potions (1 min per spell level). Your spell save DC is {{spellcasting:dc}}.</description>
			<description level="6">You have {{spell points:pool}} spell points. You can expend spell points to create spell slots, which you use to brew potions (1 min per spell level). Your spell save DC is {{spellcasting:dc}}. You can use spell points to create one slot of each level of 6th or higher, after which you can’t create another slot of the same level until you finish a long rest.</description>
			<description level="10">You have {{spell points:pool}} spell points. You can expend spell points to create spell slots, which you use to brew potions (30 sec per spell level). Your spell save DC is {{spellcasting:dc}}. You can use spell points to create one slot of each level of 6th or higher, after which you can’t create another slot of the same level until you finish a long rest.</description>
		</sheet>
		<spellcasting name="Alchemist" ability="Intelligence" allowReplace="true">
			<list>Alchemist</list>
		</spellcasting>
		<rules>
			<stat name="spell points:pool" value="4" level="1" />
			<stat name="spell points:pool" value="2" level="2" />
			<stat name="spell points:pool" value="8" level="3" />
			<stat name="spell points:pool" value="3" level="4" />
			<stat name="spell points:pool" value="10" level="5" />
			<stat name="spell points:pool" value="5" level="6" />
			<stat name="spell points:pool" value="6" level="7" />
			<stat name="spell points:pool" value="6" level="8" />
			<stat name="spell points:pool" value="13" level="9" />
			<stat name="spell points:pool" value="7" level="10" />
			<stat name="spell points:pool" value="9" level="11" />
			<stat name="spell points:pool" value="10" level="13" />
			<stat name="spell points:pool" value="11" level="15" />
			<stat name="spell points:pool" value="13" level="17" />
			<stat name="spell points:pool" value="7" level="18" />
			<stat name="spell points:pool" value="9" level="19" />
			<stat name="spell points:pool" value="10" level="20" />

			<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Alchemist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" number="3" level="1" spellcasting="Alchemist" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Alchemist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" level="4" spellcasting="Alchemist" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Alchemist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" level="10" spellcasting="Alchemist" />

			<select type="Spell" name="Spell (Alchemist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),1" number="4" level="1" spellcasting="Alchemist" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell (Alchemist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),1" level="2" spellcasting="Alchemist" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell (Alchemist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),1,2" level="3" spellcasting="Alchemist" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell (Alchemist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),1,2" level="4" spellcasting="Alchemist" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell (Alchemist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),1,2,3" level="5" spellcasting="Alchemist" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell (Alchemist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),1,2,3" level="6" spellcasting="Alchemist" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell (Alchemist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),1,2,3,4" level="7" spellcasting="Alchemist" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell (Alchemist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),1,2,3,4" level="8" spellcasting="Alchemist" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell (Alchemist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),1,2,3,4,5" level="9" spellcasting="Alchemist" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell (Alchemist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),1,2,3,4,5" level="10" spellcasting="Alchemist" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell (Alchemist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),1,2,3,4,5,6" level="11" spellcasting="Alchemist" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell (Alchemist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),1,2,3,4,5,6" level="12" spellcasting="Alchemist" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell (Alchemist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),1,2,3,4,5,6,7" level="13" spellcasting="Alchemist" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell (Alchemist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),1,2,3,4,5,6,7" level="14" spellcasting="Alchemist" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell (Alchemist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8" level="15" spellcasting="Alchemist" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell (Alchemist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8" level="16" spellcasting="Alchemist" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell (Alchemist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9" level="17" spellcasting="Alchemist" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell (Alchemist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9" level="18" spellcasting="Alchemist" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell (Alchemist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9" level="19" spellcasting="Alchemist" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spell (Alchemist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9" level="20" spellcasting="Alchemist" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Foraging Adept" type="Class Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_CLASS_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_FORAGING_ADEPT">
		<description>
			<p><em>1st-level alchemist feature</em></p>
			<p>Your time spent gathering materials for your potions has honed your foraging skills. You gain advantage on Wisdom (Survival) checks made to forage for food, water, or ingredients.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have advantage on Wisdom (Survival) checks made to forage for food, water, or ingredients.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Alchemical Pursuit" type="Class Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_CLASS_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_ALCHEMICAL_PURSUIT">
		<description>
			<p><em>2nd-level alchemist feature</em></p>
			<p>You can choose to specialize in one of the many forms of alchemy, honing your skills in a single area to a fine point. Choose one of the alchemical pursuits listed at the end of the class description. Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, 14th, and 18th level.</p>
			<h5>PURSUIT SPELLS</h5>
			<p>Each pursuit has a list of spells—its pursuit spells—that you learn at the alchemist levels noted in the pursuit description. Pursuit spells don’t count against your number of alchemist spells known.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you have a pursuit spell that doesn’t appear on the alchemist spell list, the spell is nonetheless an alchemist spell for you.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Archetype" name="Alchemical Pursuit" supports="Alchemical Pursuit" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_CLASS_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>When you reach 4th Level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Alchemist 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Alchemist,4" level="4" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Alchemist 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Alchemist,8" level="8" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Alchemist 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Alchemist,12" level="12" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Alchemist 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Alchemist,16" level="16" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Alchemist 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Alchemist,19" level="19" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Brew Cycling" type="Class Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_CLASS_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_BREW_CYCLING">
		<description>
			<p><em>5th-level alchemist feature</em></p>
			<p>You may spend 1 minute with a brewed spell and your alchemist’s supplies pulling the magical essence from your unneeded potions to recycle it for something else. The cycled potion becomes inert slime and you regain any spell points expended to brew that spell.</p>
			<p class="indent">Alternatively, if you expended spell slots gained from another class to brew that spell, you regain an expended spell slot of that level instead.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You may spend 1 minute with a brewed spell and your alchemist’s supplies to recycle it, regaining the spell points used to brew it.</description>
			<description level="10">You may spend 30 minute with a brewed spell and your alchemist’s supplies to recycle it, regaining the spell points used to brew it.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Potion Expert" type="Class Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_CLASS_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_POTION_EXPERT">
		<description>
			<p><em>10th-level alchemist feature</em></p>
			<p>You can effortlessly synthesize and identify potions. The time it takes you to brew and cycle spells is halved.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, if you spend at least 1 minute inspecting a potion, you learn its nature. This applies to both brewed spells and magic items, such as a potion of heroism or a potion of poison.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>If you spend at least 1 minute inspecting a potion, you learn its nature.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Perfect Alchemy" type="Class Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_CLASS_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_PERFECT_ALCHEMY">
		<description>
			<p><em>20th-level alchemist feature</em></p>
			<p>You can create sublime magical brilliance in liquid form. Whenever you utilize a brewed spell of 5th-level or lower with a duration of 1 minute or greater, you may imbue that spell with an incredible alchemical power. The brewed spell’s duration is for 24 hours (unless it would already last longer) and does not require concentration if it otherwise would.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you have used this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>When you utilize a brewed spell of 5th-level or lower with a duration of 1 minute or greater, its duration becomes 24 hours and it no longer requires concentration.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

    <!-- Pursuit of the Creator -->
    <element name="Pursuit of the Creator" type="Archetype" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_ALCHEMIST_PURSUIT_OF_THE_CREATOR">
		<supports>Alchemical Pursuit</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Life is a complex creation. Anyone can create an anatomical replication of something with enough study and the right tools, but none can make them any more than that: a replica. Those of the Pursuit of the Creator seek that exact goal, to create life from clay and magic: a true homunculus.</p>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATOR_PURSUIT_SPELLS" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATOR_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATOR_ADAPTABLE_CREATION" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATOR_RESILIENT_CREATION" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATOR_ADVANCED_CREATION" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATOR_MYRIAD_FORMS" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>Those of the Pursuit of the Creator seek that exact goal, to create life from clay and magic: a true homunculus.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATOR_PURSUIT_SPELLS" level="2" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATOR_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM" level="2" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATOR_ADAPTABLE_CREATION" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATOR_RESILIENT_CREATION" level="10" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATOR_ADVANCED_CREATION" level="14" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATOR_MYRIAD_FORMS" level="18" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Pursuit Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATOR_PURSUIT_SPELLS">
		<description>
			<p>You gain pursuit spells at the alchemist levels listed.</p>
			<h5>Creator Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Alchemist Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>false life, protection from evil and good</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>gentle repose, Maximilian’s earthen grasp</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><i>life transference, summon construct</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><i>fabricate, stone shape</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><i>creation, summon ouroboros </i></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FALSE_LIFE" level="2" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_EVIL_AND_GOOD" level="2" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GENTLE_REPOSE" level="3" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MAXIMILIANS_EARTHEN_GRASP" level="3" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_LIFE_TRANSFERENCE" level="5" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_SPELL_SUMMON_CONSTRUCT" level="5" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FABRICATE" level="7" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STONE_SHAPE" level="7" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATION" level="9" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_SPELL_SUMMON_OUROBOROS" level="9" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Alchemical Lifeform" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATOR_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM">
		<description>
			<p>You can combine alchemical ingredients with clay, blood and a spark of magic to craft a loyal lifeform: your alchemical lifeform. You may spend 1 hour with your alchemist supplies to craft an alchemical lifeform, during which you must expend 10 gp worth of fine materials.</p>
			<p class="indent">The lifeform uses the Alchemical Lifeform stat block. When you create your alchemical lifeform, choose its form: Guardian, Revitalizer, or Striker, which determines certain traits on its stat block.</p>
			<p class="indent">Your lifeform is sculpted to look however you choose, as long as it still counts as a Tiny or Small creature and has both legs and wings when you bring it to life.</p>
			<p class="indent">Your alchemical lifeform is loyal only to you and follows your commands to the letter.</p>
			<p class="indent">Whilst you have an alchemical lifeform, you cannot create another and any attempts to do so result in failure. You may however expend materials over 1 hour, as if creating a lifeform, to change the form of your current lifeform, granting it the benefits of a long rest in the process.</p>
			<p class="indent">In combat, the lifeform shares your initiative count, but it takes its turn immediately after yours. The only action it takes on its turn is the Dodge action, unless you take a bonus action on your turn to command it to take one of the actions in its stat block or to take the Dash, Disengage, Help, or Hide action.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_STATBLOCK_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You may spend 1 hour with your alchemist supplies to craft an alchemical lifeform, during which you must expend 10 gp worth of fine materials.&#13;
			The lifeform uses the Alchemical Lifeform stat block. When you create your alchemical lifeform, choose its form: Guardian, Revitalizer, or Striker, which determines certain traits on its stat block.&#13;
			Your lifeform is sculpted to look however you choose, as long as it still counts as a Tiny or Small creature and has both legs and wings when you bring it to life.&#13;
			Your alchemical lifeform is loyal only to you and follows your commands to the letter.&#13;
			Whilst you have an alchemical lifeform, you cannot create another and any attempts to do so result in failure. You may however expend materials over 1 hour, as if creating a lifeform, to change the form of your current lifeform, granting it the benefits of a long rest in the process.&#13;
			In combat, the lifeform shares your initiative count, but it takes its turn immediately after yours. The only action it takes on its turn is the Dodge action, unless you take a bonus action on your turn to command it to take one of the actions in its stat block or to take the Dash, Disengage, Help, or Hide action.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Companion" name="Alchemical Lifeform Form" supports="Alchemical Form" default="ID_WOTC_DTE_COMPANION_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM_1" requirements="!ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATOR_RESILIENT_CREATION" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Adaptable Creation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATOR_ADAPTABLE_CREATION">
		<description>
			<p>You can construct more versatile creations. Your lifeform’s attacks count as magical for the purposes of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, your alchemical lifeform gains two of the following additional features:</p>
			<ul>
				<li><strong>Amorphous.</strong> The lifeform can move through a space as narrow as 1-inch wide without squeezing.</li>
				<li><strong>Amphibious.</strong> The lifeform can breathe air and water.</li>
				<li><strong>Arcane Sight.</strong> Magical darkness doesn’t impede the lifeform’s darkvision.</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Resistance.</strong> Choose one of the following damage types: acid, cold, fire, lightning, necrotic, radiant, or thunder. The lifeform gains resistance to the chosen damage type. The lifeform can gain the benefits of this trait more than once.</li>
				<li><strong>False Appearance.</strong> Choose an object of your lifeform’s size. You re-sculpt your lifeform’s form to look like that object. While the lifeform remains motionless, it is indistinguishable from the chosen object.</li>
				<li><strong>Keen Senses.</strong> Choose two of the following senses: hearing, sight, and smell. The lifeform gains advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks made with the chosen senses.</li>
				<li><strong>Spider Climb.</strong> The lifeform can climb difficult surfaces, including upside down on ceilings, without needing to make an ability check. Additionally, the lifeform gains a climb speed of 40 ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Variable Illumination.</strong> The lifeform sheds bright light in a 5 to 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional number of feet equal to the chosen radius. The lifeform can alter the radius as a bonus action.</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent">Your lifeform cannot gain the benefits of the same trait more than once.</p>
			<p class="indent">The number of traits your lifeform can have increases as you gain alchemist levels, increasing by one at 10th, 14th, and 18th level.</p>
			<p class="indent">During a long rest, you may choose one or more of the traits gained with this feature, spending 1 hour with your alchemical lifeform and alchemist’s supplies, expending 5 gp for each chosen trait. For each of those traits, replace it with a different trait from the list.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your lifeform’s attacks count as magical for the purposes of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical damage. Additionally, your alchemical lifeform gains {{adaptable creation:traits}} of the following additional features:&#13;
			• Amorphous. The lifeform can move through a space as narrow as 1-inch wide without squeezing.&#13;
			• Amphibious. The lifeform can breathe air and water.&#13;
			• Arcane Sight. Magical darkness doesn’t impede the lifeform’s darkvision.&#13;
			• Damage Resistance. Choose one of the following damage types: acid, cold, fire, lightning, necrotic, radiant, or thunder. The lifeform gains resistance to the chosen damage type. The lifeform can gain the benefits of this trait more than once.&#13;
			• False Appearance. Choose an object of your lifeform’s size. You re-sculpt your lifeform’s form to look like that object. While the lifeform remains motionless, it is indistinguishable from the chosen object.&#13;
			• Keen Senses. Choose two of the following senses: hearing, sight, and smell. The lifeform gains advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks made with the chosen senses.&#13;
			• Spider Climb. The lifeform can climb difficult surfaces, including upside down on ceilings, without needing to make an ability check. Additionally, the lifeform gains a climb speed of 40 ft.&#13;
			• Variable Illumination. The lifeform sheds bright light in a 5 to 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional number of feet equal to the chosen radius. The lifeform can alter the radius as a bonus action.&#13;
			During a long rest, you may choose one or more of the traits gained with this feature, spending 1 hour with your alchemical lifeform and alchemist’s supplies, expending 5 gp for each chosen trait. For each of those traits, replace it with a different trait from the list.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="adaptable creation:traits" value="2" />
			<stat name="adaptable creation:traits" value="1" level="10" />
			<stat name="adaptable creation:traits" value="1" level="14" />
			<stat name="adaptable creation:traits" value="1" level="18" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Resilient Creation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATOR_RESILIENT_CREATION">
		<description>
			<p>You have imbued a greater resolve in your alchemical creation. Your lifeform gains advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, your lifeform gains resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical attacks.</p>
			<p class="indent">Furthermore, when you create your lifeform, you may choose for it to be Medium, rather than Small or Tiny.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your lifeform gains advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects. Additionally, your lifeform gains resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical attacks. Furthermore, when you create your lifeform, you may choose for it to be Medium, rather than Small or Tiny.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Companion" name="Alchemical Lifeform Form" supports="Alchemical Form" default="ID_WOTC_DTE_COMPANION_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM_2" requirements="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATOR_RESILIENT_CREATION" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Advanced Creation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATOR_ADVANCED_CREATION">
		<description>
			<p>The benefits granted by the different forms your alchemical lifeform can take improve in the following ways:</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Guardian.</b> The lifeform gets a special reaction that you can take once each round, except on the turn it takes its normal reaction. It can use this special reaction only to use its Protection reaction. Additionally, the lifeform gains a +2 bonus to its AC.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Striker.</b> The lifeform doesn’t provoke an opportunity attack when it moves out of an enemy’s reach. Additionally, the lifeform has advantage on an attack roll against a creature if at least one of the lifeform’s allies is within 5 feet of the creature and the ally isn’t incapacitated.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Revitalizer.</b> The lifeform gains a pool of hit points equal to twice your alchemist level. Whenever it uses its Restore feature, it may remove any number of hit points from this pool, which counts as reducing its current hit points for that trait. When the lifeform completes a long rest, this pool is fully replenished. Additionally, a creature can gain the benefits of the lifeform’s Restore action twice before it must complete short or long rest to do so again, instead of once.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The benefits granted by the different forms your alchemical lifeform can take improve in the following ways:&#13;
			• Guardian. The lifeform gets a special reaction that you can take once each round, except on the turn it takes its normal reaction. It can use this special reaction only to use its Protection reaction. Additionally, the lifeform gains a +2 bonus to its AC.&#13;
			• Striker. The lifeform doesn’t provoke an opportunity attack when it moves out of an enemy’s reach. Additionally, the lifeform has advantage on an attack roll against a creature if at least one of the lifeform’s allies is within 5 feet of the creature and the ally isn’t incapacitated.&#13;
			• Revitalizer. The lifeform gains a pool of hit points equal to twice your alchemist level. Whenever it uses its Restore feature, it may remove any number of hit points from this pool, which counts as reducing its current hit points for that trait. When the lifeform completes a long rest, this pool is fully replenished. Additionally, a creature can gain the benefits of the lifeform’s Restore action twice before it must complete short or long rest to do so again, instead of once.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Myriad Forms" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATOR_MYRIAD_FORMS">
		<description>
			<p>You can have your lifeform assume just about any form. As an action on your turn, if your lifeform is within 60 feet of you, you may point to it, empowering it with a surge of alchemical reactions. It transforms into a creature of challenge rating 10 or lower, as per the shapechange spell, except that its languages and speech abilities do not change to match its new form.</p>
			<p class="indent">Whilst in this new form, the lifeform retains the actions and traits gained from its chosen form and the chosen traits from your Adaptable Creation feature.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once your lifeform has transformed in this way, it cannot do so again until 7 days have passed.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, when you create your lifeform, you may choose for it to be Large, rather than Medium, Small or Tiny.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/7 Days" action="Action">
			<description>If your lifeform is within 60 feet of you, you may point to it, empowering it with a surge of alchemical reactions. It transforms into a creature of challenge rating 10 or lower, as per the shapechange spell, except that its languages and speech abilities do not change to match its new form.&#13;
			Whilst in this new form, the lifeform retains the actions and traits gained from its chosen form and the chosen traits from your Adaptable Creation feature.&#13;
			Additionally, when you create your lifeform, you may choose for it to be Large, rather than Medium, Small or Tiny.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
<!-- Alchemical Lifeform Form -->
	<element name="Alchemical Lifeform" type="Companion" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_COMPANION_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM_1">
		<supports>Alchemical Form</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You can combine alchemical ingredients with clay, blood and a spark of magic to craft a loyal lifeform: your alchemical lifeform. You may spend 1 hour with your alchemist supplies to craft an alchemical lifeform, during which you must expend 10 gp worth of fine materials.</p>
			<p class="indent">The lifeform uses the Alchemical Lifeform stat block. When you create your alchemical lifeform, choose its form: Guardian, Revitalizer, or Striker, which determines certain traits on its stat block.</p>
			<p class="indent">Your lifeform is sculpted to look however you choose, as long as it still counts as a Tiny or Small creature and has both legs and wings when you bring it to life.</p>
			<p class="indent">Your alchemical lifeform is loyal only to you and follows your commands to the letter.</p>
			<p class="indent">Whilst you have an alchemical lifeform, you cannot create another and any attempts to do so result in failure. You may however expend materials over 1 hour, as if creating a lifeform, to change the form of your current lifeform, granting it the benefits of a long rest in the process.</p>
			<p class="indent">In combat, the lifeform shares your initiative count, but it takes its turn immediately after yours. The only action it takes on its turn is the Dodge action, unless you take a bonus action on your turn to command it to take one of the actions in its stat block or to take the Dash, Disengage, Help, or Hide action.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="size">Tiny or Small</set>
			<set name="type">Construct</set>
			<set name="alignment">unaligned</set>
			<set name="ac">12 + PB</set>
			<set name="hp">5 + five times your alchemist level</set>
			<set name="speed">20 ft., fly 40 ft.</set>
			<set name="strength">4</set>
			<set name="dexterity">15</set>
			<set name="constitution">11</set>
			<set name="intelligence">10</set>
			<set name="wisdom">10</set>
			<set name="charisma">7</set>
			<set name="immunities">poison</set>
			<set name="conditionImmunities">charmed, frightened, poisoned</set>            
			<set name="senses">darkvision 60 ft., passive Perception 10</set>
			<set name="languages">understands the languages of its creator but can’t speak</set>
			<set name="challenge">-</set>
			<set name="traits">ID_WOTC_DTE_COMPANION_TRAIT_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM_ENHANCED_STRIKES,ID_WOTC_DTE_COMPANION_TRAIT_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM_REGENERATION,ID_WOTC_DTE_COMPANION_TRAIT_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM_TELEPATHIC_BOND</set>
			<set name="actions">ID_WOTC_DTE_COMPANION_ACTION_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM_STRIKE,ID_WOTC_DTE_COMPANION_ACTION_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM_RESTORE, ID_WOTC_DTE_COMPANION_ACTION_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM_COMBAT_ASSISTANCE</set>
			<set name="reactions">ID_WOTC_DTE_COMPANION_ACTION_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM_PROTECTION</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="companion:ac" value="12" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="companion:ac" value="proficiency" bonus="proficiency" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="5" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:alchemist" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:alchemist" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:alchemist" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:alchemist" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:alchemist" />
			<stat name="companion:speed" value="20" bonus="base" />	
			<stat name="companion:speed:fly" value="40" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Alchemical Lifeform" type="Companion" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_COMPANION_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM_2">
		<requirements>ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATOR_RESILIENT_CREATION</requirements>
		<supports>Alchemical Form</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You can combine alchemical ingredients with clay, blood and a spark of magic to craft a loyal lifeform: your alchemical lifeform. You may spend 1 hour with your alchemist supplies to craft an alchemical lifeform, during which you must expend 10 gp worth of fine materials.</p>
			<p class="indent">The lifeform uses the Alchemical Lifeform stat block. When you create your alchemical lifeform, choose its form: Guardian, Revitalizer, or Striker, which determines certain traits on its stat block.</p>
			<p class="indent">Your lifeform is sculpted to look however you choose, as long as it still counts as a Tiny or Small creature and has both legs and wings when you bring it to life.</p>
			<p class="indent">Your alchemical lifeform is loyal only to you and follows your commands to the letter.</p>
			<p class="indent">Whilst you have an alchemical lifeform, you cannot create another and any attempts to do so result in failure. You may however expend materials over 1 hour, as if creating a lifeform, to change the form of your current lifeform, granting it the benefits of a long rest in the process.</p>
			<p class="indent">In combat, the lifeform shares your initiative count, but it takes its turn immediately after yours. The only action it takes on its turn is the Dodge action, unless you take a bonus action on your turn to command it to take one of the actions in its stat block or to take the Dash, Disengage, Help, or Hide action.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="size">Tiny, Small or Medium</set>
			<set name="type">Construct</set>
			<set name="alignment">unaligned</set>
			<set name="ac">12 + PB</set>
			<set name="hp">5 + five times your alchemist level</set>
			<set name="speed">20 ft., fly 40 ft.</set>
			<set name="strength">4</set>
			<set name="dexterity">15</set>
			<set name="constitution">11</set>
			<set name="intelligence">10</set>
			<set name="wisdom">10</set>
			<set name="charisma">7</set>
			<set name="resistances">bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks</set>
			<set name="immunities">poison</set>
			<set name="conditionImmunities">charmed, frightened, poisoned</set>            
			<set name="senses">darkvision 60 ft., passive Perception 10</set>
			<set name="languages">understands the languages of its creator but can’t speak</set>
			<set name="challenge">-</set>
			<set name="traits">ID_WOTC_DTE_COMPANION_TRAIT_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM_ENHANCED_STRIKES,ID_WOTC_DTE_COMPANION_TRAIT_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM_REGENERATION,ID_WOTC_DTE_COMPANION_TRAIT_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM_TELEPATHIC_BOND,ID_WOTC_DTE_COMPANION_TRAIT_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM_RESILIENT_CREATION</set>
			<set name="actions">ID_WOTC_DTE_COMPANION_ACTION_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM_STRIKE,ID_WOTC_DTE_COMPANION_ACTION_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM_RESTORE,ID_WOTC_DTE_COMPANION_ACTION_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM_COMBAT_ASSISTANCE</set>
			<set name="reactions">ID_WOTC_DTE_COMPANION_ACTION_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM_PROTECTION</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="companion:ac" value="12" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="companion:ac" value="proficiency" bonus="proficiency" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="5" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:alchemist" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:alchemist" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:alchemist" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:alchemist" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:alchemist" />
			<stat name="companion:speed" value="20" bonus="base" />	
			<stat name="companion:speed:fly" value="40" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Enhanced Strikes (Striker Only)" type="Companion Trait" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_COMPANION_TRAIT_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM_ENHANCED_STRIKES">
		<description>
			<p>The lifeforms Strike attack deals an additional 2 (1d4) force damage. The additional damage increases as you gain alchemist levels, increasing by 1d4 at 10th (2d4), and 18th (3d4) level.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The lifeforms Strike attack deals an additional 2 (1d4) force damage.</description>
			<description level="10">The lifeforms Strike attack deals an additional 4 (2d4) force damage.</description>
			<description level="18">The lifeforms Strike attack deals an additional 6 (3d4) force damage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Regeneration (Guardian Only)" type="Companion Trait" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_COMPANION_TRAIT_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM_REGENERATION">
		<description>
			<p>The lifeform regains hit points equal to your proficiency bonus at the start of its turn if it has at least 1 hit point.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The lifeform regains hit points equal to your proficiency bonus at the start of its turn if it has at least 1 hit point.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Telepathic Bond" type="Companion Trait" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_COMPANION_TRAIT_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM_TELEPATHIC_BOND">
		<description>
			<p>While the lifeform is within 1-mile of its creator, it can magically convey what it senses to its creator, and the two can communicate telepathically.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>While the lifeform is within 1-mile of its creator, it can magically convey what it senses to its creator, and the two can communicate telepathically.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Strike" type="Companion Action" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_COMPANION_ACTION_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM_STRIKE">
		<description>
			<p><i>Melee Weapon Attack:</i> +your spellcasting ability modifier to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. <i>Hit:</i> 1d6 + PB bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage (your choice when you create the lifeform)</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Melee Weapon Attack: +your spellcasting ability modifier to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1d6 + PB bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage (your choice when you create the lifeform)</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Restore (Revitalizer Only)" type="Companion Action" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_COMPANION_ACTION_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM_RESTORE">
		<description>
			<p>The lifeform touches a creature, reducing its current hit points by an amount up to twice your alchemist level or its current remaining hit points, whichever is lower. The target regains that many hit points. Once a creature has regained hit points in this way, it can't do so again until it completes a short or long rest. If the lifeform targets a creature with 0 hit points, it must reduce its current hit points by the maximum amount and the target regains only 1 hit point.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The lifeform touches a creature, reducing its current hit points by an amount up to twice your alchemist level or its current remaining hit points, whichever is lower. The target regains that many hit points. Once a creature has regained hit points in this way, it can't do so again until it completes a short or long rest. If the lifeform targets a creature with 0 hit points, it must reduce its current hit points by the maximum amount and the target regains only 1 hit point.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Combat Assistance (Striker Only) (Bonus Action) " type="Companion Action" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_COMPANION_ACTION_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM_COMBAT_ASSISTANCE">
		<description>
			<p>The lifeform takes the Help action to assist an allied creature in attacking a creature hostile to its creator.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The lifeform takes the Help action to assist an allied creature in attacking a creature hostile to its creator.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Protection (Guardian Only)" type="Companion Action" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_COMPANION_ACTION_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM_PROTECTION">
		<description>
			<p>Whenever a creature within 5 feet of the lifeform would become the target of an attack, the lifeform interposes itself, becoming the target of that attack instead.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Whenever a creature within 5 feet of the lifeform would become the target of an attack, the lifeform interposes itself, becoming the target of that attack instead.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Resilient Creation" type="Companion Trait" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_COMPANION_TRAIT_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM_RESILIENT_CREATION">
		<description>
			<p>Your lifeform gains advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your lifeform gains advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Alchemical Lifeform" type="Information" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_STATBLOCK_ALCHEMICAL_LIFEFORM">
		<description>
			<p style="margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Tiny or Small construct</em></p>
			<h4 style="margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 12 + PB</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> 5 + five times your alchemist level</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 20 ft., fly 40 ft.</li>
			</ul>
			<table style="text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>4 (-3)</td><td>15 (+2)</td><td>11 (+0)</td><td>10 (+0)</td><td>10 (+0)</td><td>7 (-2)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Damage Immunities</strong> poison</li>
				<li><strong>Condition Immunities</strong> charmed, frightened, poisoned</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 60 ft., passive Perception 10</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> understands the languages of its creator but can’t speak</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> —</li>
				<li><strong>Proficiency Bonus (PB)</strong> equals your bonus</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style="margin-top:5px; margin-bottom:10px" />
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Enhanced Strikes (Striker Only).</strong> The lifeforms Strike attack deals an additional 2 (1d4) force damage. The additional damage increases as you gain alchemist levels, increasing by 1d4 at 10th (2d4), and 18th (3d4) level.</li>
				<li><strong>Regeneration (Guardian Only).</strong> The lifeform regains hit points equal to your proficiency bonus at the start of its turn if it has at least 1 hit point.</li>
				<li><strong>Telepathic Bond.</strong> While the lifeform is within 1-mile of its creator, it can magically convey what it senses to its creator, and the two can communicate telepathically.</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style="margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Strike.</strong> <em>Melee Weapon Attack:</em> your spellcasting ability modifier to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. <em>Hit:</em> 1d6 + PB bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage (your choice when you create the lifeform).</li>
				<li><strong>Restore (Revitalizer Only).</strong> The lifeform touches a creature, reducing its current hit points by an amount up to twice your alchemist level or its current remaining hit points, whichever is lower. The target regains that many hit points. Once a creature has regained hit points in this way, it can't do so again until it completes a short or long rest. If the lifeform targets a creature with 0 hit points, it must reduce its current hit points by the maximum amount and the target regains only 1 hit point.</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style="margin-top:10px">Bonus Actions</h4>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Combat Assistance (Striker Only).</strong> The lifeform takes the Help action to assist an allied creature in attacking a creature hostile to its creator.</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style="margin-top:10px">Reactions</h4>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Protection (Guardian Only).</strong> Whenever a creature within 5 feet of the lifeform would become the target of an attack, the lifeform interposes itself, becoming the target of that attack instead.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
	</element>
	
<!-- Pursuit of the Healer -->    
	<element name="Pursuit of the Healer" type="Archetype" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_ALCHEMIST_PURSUIT_OF_THE_HEALER">
		<supports>Alchemical Pursuit</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Many a humble apothecary brews tonics and tinctures for the sick, but it is those of the Pursuit of the Healer that aim toward the perfect restorative elixirs. Master physicians and treaters of any ill, healers strive for the perfect cure-all, the perfect panacea.</p>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEALER_PURSUIT_SPELLS" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEALER_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEALER_FIRST_AID" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEALER_INVERSE_HARM" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEALER_OVERHEAL" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEALER_REGENERATOR" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEALER_TRUE_PANACEA" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>Master physicians and treaters of any ill, healers strive for the perfect cure-all, the perfect panacea.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEALER_PURSUIT_SPELLS" level="2" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEALER_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="2" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEALER_FIRST_AID" level="2" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEALER_INVERSE_HARM" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEALER_OVERHEAL" level="10" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEALER_REGENERATOR" level="14" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEALER_TRUE_PANACEA" level="18" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Pursuit Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEALER_PURSUIT_SPELLS">
		<description>
			<p>You gain pursuit spells at the alchemist levels listed.</p>
			<h5>Healer Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Alchemist Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>healing word, heroism</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>aid, lesser restoration</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><i>mass healing word, revivify</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><i>death ward, healing vapors</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><i>mass cure wounds, raise dead</i></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEALING_WORD" level="2" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEROISM" level="2" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AID" level="3" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LESSER_RESTORATION" level="3" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_HEALING_WORD" level="5" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REVIVIFY" level="5" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD" level="7" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_SPELL_HEALING_VAPORS" level="7" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_CURE_WOUNDS" level="9" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAISE_DEAD" level="9" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEALER_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency in the Medicine skill.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="First Aid" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEALER_FIRST_AID">
		<description>
			<p>You can quickly administer aid to the severely injured. You can attempt to stabilize a creature as a bonus action on your turn.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, you may use a bonus action to administer healing reagents to a creature you touch. The target may expend a number of Hit Dice up to your proficiency bonus, rolling them and regaining hit points as if expended during a short rest.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, regaining all expended uses whenever you complete a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="{{proficiency}}/Long Rest" action="Bonus Action">
			<description>You can attempt to stabilize a creature as a bonus action on your turn.&#13;
			Additionally, you may use a bonus action to administer healing reagents to a creature you touch. The target may expend a number of Hit Dice up to {{proficiency}}, rolling them and regaining hit points as if expended during a short rest.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Inverse Harm" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEALER_INVERSE_HARM">
		<description>
			<p>You have developed healing salves with reactive release, capable of repelling even the most devastating attacks. Whenever a creature within 30 feet of you would take damage, you can use your reaction to reduce that damage by half. The target then gains temporary hit points equal to the damage taken, which last for 1 minute.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you have used this reaction, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest, unless you spend two uses of your First Aid feature to use it again.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Short Rest" action="Reaction">
			<description>Whenever a creature within 30 feet of you would take damage, you can use your reaction to reduce that damage by half. The target then gains temporary hit points equal to the damage taken, which last for 1 minute.&#13;
			Once you have used this reaction, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest, unless you spend two uses of your First Aid feature to use it again.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Overheal" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEALER_OVERHEAL">
		<description>
			<p>Your healing abilities can surpass the natural fortitude of those around you. Whenever you restore hit points to one or more creatures with a brewed spell or alchemist feature, one of those creatures that you choose gains additional temporary hit points equal to your alchemist level, which last until the start of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Whenever you restore hit points to one or more creatures with a brewed spell or alchemist feature, one of those creatures that you choose gains {{level:alchemist}} temporary hit points, which last until the start of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Regenerator" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEALER_REGENERATOR">
		<description>
			<p>Your constant testing of healing alchemy on yourself has enhanced your natural healing abilities to impossible levels. You may expend Hit Dice as a bonus action on your turn, rolling it and regaining hit points as if during a short rest.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, when you use your First Aid feature on another creature, you may expend and roll your own Hit Dice to restore hit points to the target, instead of the target expending and rolling theirs.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action">
			<description>You may expend Hit Dice as a bonus action on your turn, rolling it and regaining hit points as if during a short rest.&#13;
			Additionally, when you use your First Aid feature on another creature, you may expend and roll your own Hit Dice to restore hit points to the target, instead of the target expending and rolling theirs.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="True Panacea" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEALER_TRUE_PANACEA">
		<description>
			<p>You have developed the perfect cure all. As an action on your turn, you imbue a creature with the perfect panacea. It gains the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>It regains all its hit points.</li>
				<li>It’s cured of all ongoing diseases and poisons.</li>
				<li>It gains 50 temporary hit points, which last for 8 hours.</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent">Once you have used this feature, you must complete a long rest before you may do so again.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Long Rest" action="Action">
			<description>You imbue a creature with the perfect panacea. It gains the following benefits:&#13;
			• It regains all its hit points.&#13;
			• It’s cured of all ongoing diseases and poisons.&#13;
			• It gains 50 temporary hit points, which last for 8 hours.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

<!-- Pursuit of Longevity -->
	<element name="Pursuit of Longevity" type="Archetype" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_ALCHEMIST_PURSUIT_OF_LONGEVITY">
		<supports>Alchemical Pursuit</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Those of the Pursuit of Longevity seek not simply to brew a great potion, but to brew the essences of alchemy within themselves, cultivating a perfect soul. These alchemists utilize the seven alchemical metals: lead, tin, iron, copper, quicksilver, silver, and gold, imbuing the metals’ essence into themselves, purifying their mind, body, and soul.</p>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LONGEVITY_PURSUIT_SPELLS" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LONGEVITY_ALCHEMICAL_BODY" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LONGEVITY_QUICKSILVER_STRIKE" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LONGEVITY_TENACITY_OF_THE_SILVER_AND_LEAD" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LONGEVITY_IRON_FIST" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LONGEVITY_HARMONY_OF_TIN_AND_COPPER" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LONGEVITY_FIST_OF_GOLD_AND_SILVER" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LONGEVITY_PHILOSOPHERS_STONE" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>Those of the Pursuit of Longevity seek not simply to brew a great potion, but to brew the essences of alchemy within themselves, cultivating a perfect soul.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LONGEVITY_PURSUIT_SPELLS" level="2" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LONGEVITY_ALCHEMICAL_BODY" level="2" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LONGEVITY_QUICKSILVER_STRIKE" level="2" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LONGEVITY_TENACITY_OF_THE_SILVER_AND_LEAD" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LONGEVITY_IRON_FIST" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LONGEVITY_HARMONY_OF_TIN_AND_COPPER" level="10" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LONGEVITY_FIST_OF_GOLD_AND_SILVER" level="14" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LONGEVITY_PHILOSOPHERS_STONE" level="18" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Pursuit Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LONGEVITY_PURSUIT_SPELLS">
		<description>
			<p>You gain pursuit spells at the alchemist levels listed.</p>
			<h5>Longevity Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Alchemist Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>absorb elements, shield</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>alter self, enhance ability</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><i>aura of vitality, intellect fortress</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><i>death ward, stoneskin</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><i>skill empowerment, summon ouroboros</i></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ABSORB_ELEMENTS" level="2" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHIELD" level="2" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALTER_SELF" level="3" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENHANCE_ABILITY" level="3" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AURA_OF_VITALITY" level="5" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_SPELL_INTELLECT_FORTRESS" level="5" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD" level="7" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STONESKIN" level="7" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SKILL_EMPOWERMENT" level="9" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_SPELL_SUMMON_OUROBOROS" level="9" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Alchemical Body" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LONGEVITY_ALCHEMICAL_BODY">
		<description>
			<p>You start along your journey of self-improvement through alchemical augmentation. You gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>While you are not wearing any armor, your Armor Class equals 10 + your Constitution modifier + your Intelligence modifier.</li>
				<li>You can use Constitution instead of Strength for the attack and damage rolls of your unarmed strikes.</li>
				<li>You can roll a d4 in place of the normal damage of your unarmed strike.</li>
				<li>When you use your action to utilize a brewed spell, you can make one unarmed strike as a bonus action this turn.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You gain the following benefits:&#13;
			• You can use Constitution instead of Strength for the attack and damage rolls of your unarmed strikes.&#13;
			• You can roll a d4 in place of the normal damage of your unarmed strike.&#13;
			• When you use your action to utilize a brewed spell, you can make one unarmed strike as a bonus action this turn.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:alchemical body" value="10" />
			<stat name="ac:alchemical body" value="constitution:modifier" />
			<stat name="ac:alchemical body" value="intelligence:modifier" />
			<stat name="ac:calculation" value="ac:alchemical body" bonus="calculation" equipped="[armor:none]" alt="Alchemical Body" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Quicksilver Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LONGEVITY_QUICKSILVER_STRIKE">
		<description>
			<p>Your body shimmers like quicksilver when you strike. When you hit a creature with an unarmed strike, you can move up to 10 feet without provoking opportunity attacks.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you hit a creature with an unarmed strike, you can move up to 10 feet without provoking opportunity attacks.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Tenacity of the Silver and Lead" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LONGEVITY_TENACITY_OF_THE_SILVER_AND_LEAD">
		<description>
			<p>You have drawn upon the strength of the seven metals to enhance your defenses. You may use a bonus action on your turn to enter an alchemically regenerative state. For 1 minute, you regain hit points equal to your proficiency bonus at the end of each of your turns. This feature can restore you to no more than half your hit point maximum and it ends early if you are reduced to 0 hit points.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, regaining all expended uses whenever you complete a long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, you may use your Constitution score in place of Strength or Dexterity for ability checks you make.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="{{proficiency}}/Long Rest" action="Bonus Action">
			<description>You may use a bonus action on your turn to enter an alchemically regenerative state. For 1 minute, you regain {{proficiency}} hit points at the end of each of your turns. This feature can restore you to no more than half your hit point maximum and it ends early if you are reduced to 0 hit points.&#13;
			Additionally, you may use your Constitution score in place of Strength or Dexterity for ability checks you make.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="athletics:misc" value="-strenght:modifier" />
			<stat name="acrobatics:misc" value="-dexterity:modifier" />
			<stat name="sleight of hand:misc" value="-dexterity:modifier" />
			<stat name="stealth:misc" value="-dexterity:modifier" />

			<stat name="athletics:misc" value="strenght:modifier" bonus="ability"/>
			<stat name="acrobatics:misc" value="dexterity:modifier" bonus="ability"/>
			<stat name="sleight of hand:misc" value="dexterity:modifier" bonus="ability"/>
			<stat name="stealth:misc" value="dexterity:modifier" bonus="ability"/>
			<stat name="athletics:misc" value="constitution:modifier" bonus="ability"/>
			<stat name="acrobatics:misc" value="constitution:modifier" bonus="ability"/>
			<stat name="sleight of hand:misc" value="constitution:modifier" bonus="ability"/>
			<stat name="stealth:misc" value="constitution:modifier" bonus="ability"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Iron Fist" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LONGEVITY_IRON_FIST">
		<description>
			<p>Your body is infused with the magical metals. Your unarmed strikes count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your unarmed strikes count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Harmony of Tin and Copper" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LONGEVITY_HARMONY_OF_TIN_AND_COPPER">
		<description>
			<p>The metallic strength you have drawn through alchemical prowess has purified your body and strengthened your resolve. You gain immunity to poison and disease.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, whenever you would be forced to make a Strength or Dexterity saving throw against an effect, you may choose to make a Constitution saving throw against that effect instead.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You gain immunity to poison and disease. Additionally, whenever you would be forced to make a Strength or Dexterity saving throw against an effect, you may choose to make a Constitution saving throw against that effect instead.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_POISON" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Fist of Gold and Silver" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LONGEVITY_FIST_OF_GOLD_AND_SILVER">
		<description>
			<p>Your strikes are permanently enhanced by the forces of raw alchemical strength. Whenever you hit a creature with an unarmed strike, the target takes an extra 2d4 force damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Whenever you hit a creature with an unarmed strike, the target takes an extra 2d4 force damage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Philosopher’s Stone" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LONGEVITY_PHILOSOPHERS_STONE">
		<description>
			<p>You have gone beyond the seven stages of alchemy, synthesizing a perfectly-focused core of alchemical power. The philosopher’s stone sits somewhere on your body, embedded in your skin. When you would be reduced to 0 hit points, you may use your reaction to instead drop to 1 hit point and expend a number of Hit Dice up to your Constitution modifier, regaining hit points as if expended during a short rest.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you have used this feature, you cannot do so again until you next complete a long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, you no longer age naturally and you cannot be aged magically.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Long Rest" action="Reaction">
			<description>When you would be reduced to 0 hit points, you may use your reaction to instead drop to 1 hit point and expend a number of Hit Dice up to {{constitution:modifier}}, regaining hit points as if expended during a short rest.&#13;
			Additionally, you no longer age naturally and you cannot be aged magically.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

<!-- Pursuit of the Mixologist -->
	<element name="Pursuit of the Mixologist" type="Archetype" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_ALCHEMIST_PURSUIT_OF_THE_MIXOLOGIST">
		<supports>Alchemical Pursuit</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Many alchemists seek a mutable potion, a brew that can be changed to fit any scenario. Those of the Pursuit of the Mixologist seek this exact path, turning one spell to another like night turns to day, with the ultimate goal of mixing the ultimate potion through methods thought impossible.</p>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MIXOLOGIST_PURSUIT_SPELLS" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MIXOLOGIST_MYSTERY_MIX" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MIXOLOGIST_ADAPTABLE_MIXTURES" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MIXOLOGIST_POTION_TUNER" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MIXOLOGIST_CHAOTIC_DEFENSE" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MIXOLOGIST_MASTER_MIXOLOGIST" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>Many alchemists seek a mutable potion, a brew that can be changed to fit any scenario.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MIXOLOGIST_PURSUIT_SPELLS" level="2" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MIXOLOGIST_MYSTERY_MIX" level="2" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MIXOLOGIST_ADAPTABLE_MIXTURES" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MIXOLOGIST_POTION_TUNER" level="10" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MIXOLOGIST_CHAOTIC_DEFENSE" level="14" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MIXOLOGIST_MASTER_MIXOLOGIST" level="18" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Pursuit Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MIXOLOGIST_PURSUIT_SPELLS">
		<description>
			<p>You gain pursuit spells at the alchemist levels listed.</p>
			<h5>Mixologist Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Alchemist Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>chaos bolt, confetti bomb</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>enlarge/reduce, mirror image</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><i>blink, hypnotic pattern</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><i>confusion, polymorph</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><i>awaken, mislead</i></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CHAOS_BOLT" level="2" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_SPELL_CONFETTI_BOMB" level="2" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENLARGE_REDUCE" level="3" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIRROR_IMAGE" level="3" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINK" level="5" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HYPNOTIC_PATTERN" level="5" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONFUSION" level="7" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POLYMORPH" level="7" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AWAKEN" level="9" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISLEAD" level="9" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Mystery Mix" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MIXOLOGIST_MYSTERY_MIX">
		<description>
			<p>You can quickly retool any potion into a chaotic concoction to flummox any foe. As a bonus action: with alchemist’s supplies in hand, you may perform alchemical adjustments to one of your brewed spells, retooling its magic into a mysterious mixture. Roll your Mystery die twice, which is a d6, then consult the Mystery Mix table and choose a result. The brewed spells magic is lost, replaced with the chosen effect, at a level equal to the altered spell.</p>
			<p class="indent">If a mixture forces another creature to make a saving throw, the DC is equal to your alchemist spell save DC.</p>
			<p class="indent">As a part of your bonus action to mix this new concoction, you may use it. Alternatively, you may expend a bonus action on subsequent turns to use it then.</p>
			<p class="indent">To use a mixture, you must throw it toward a target that you can see within 30 feet of you.</p>
			<p class="indent">The mixture’s magic is lost after 1 minute, rendering it a useless slime.</p>
			<h5>Mystery Mix</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Mystery Die</td><td>Effect</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>Healing Mix. The target regains hit points equal to your alchemist level + twice the spell level.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>Gravitic Mix. The target must make a Strength saving throw. On a failure, the target is launched a number of feet into the air equal to ten times the spell level. On a success, the target is launched only half that distance and when it falls, it can land on its feet.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>Power Mix. The target adds the spell level to the damage of each weapon damage roll it makes until the end of its next turn.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>Corrosive Mix. The target must make a Constitution saving throw. Roll a number of d6 equal to the spell level. On a failure, the target takes the result + your Intelligence modifier as acid damage. On a failure, the target takes half the result + your Intelligence modifier as acid damage.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td>Protective Mix. The target reduces all incoming damage it takes until the end of your next turn by an amount equal to the spell level.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td>Mysterious Mix. A number of mixed blobs equal to 1 + the brewed spell’s level appear in the nearest unoccupied spaces to the target. See these creatures’ game statistics in the Mysterious Blob stat block, which have hit points equal to three times the spell level and use your proficiency bonus (PB) in several places. The blobs take their turn immediately after yours on the same initiative count and obey your commands. When reduced to 0 hit points or after 1 minute, they turn to harmless goo and are destroyed.</td></tr>
			</table>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_STATBLOCK_MYSTERIOUS_BLOB" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action">
			<description>With alchemist’s supplies in hand, you may perform alchemical adjustments to one of your brewed spells, retooling its magic into a mysterious mixture. Roll your Mystery die twice, which is a d6, then consult the Mystery Mix table and choose a result. The brewed spells magic is lost, replaced with the chosen effect, at a level equal to the altered spell.&#13;
			If a mixture forces another creature to make a saving throw, the DC is equal to your alchemist spell save DC.&#13;
			As a part of your bonus action to mix this new concoction, you may use it. Alternatively, you may expend a bonus action on subsequent turns to use it then.&#13;
			To use a mixture, you must throw it toward a target that you can see within 30 feet of you.&#13;
			The mixture’s magic is lost after 1 minute, rendering it a useless slime.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Adaptable Mixtures" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MIXOLOGIST_ADAPTABLE_MIXTURES">
		<description>
			<p>You can create alchemical wonders and blunders alike with incredible ease. When you use your Mystery Mix feature, you may choose not to alter a brewed spell, instead creating a mixture from scratch. If you do, you roll your Mystery die only once, and when the mixture refers to the altered spell’s level, it is considered 1st-level. This level increases as you gain levels in this class, increasing by one spell level at 10th (2nd-level), 14th (3rd-level), and 18th (4th-level).</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, regaining all expended uses when you complete a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="{{proficiency}}/Long Rest">
			<description>When you use your Mystery Mix feature, you may choose not to alter a brewed spell, instead creating a mixture from scratch. If you do, you roll your Mystery die only once, and when the mixture refers to the altered spell’s level, it is considered {{adaptable mixtures:level}}-level. </description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="adaptable mixtures:level" value="1" />
			<stat name="adaptable mixtures:level" value="1" level="10" />
			<stat name="adaptable mixtures:level" value="1" level="14" />
			<stat name="adaptable mixtures:level" value="1" level="18" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Potion Tuner" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MIXOLOGIST_POTION_TUNER">
		<description>
			<p>Your ability to mix and combine potions is greatly enhanced. As a bonus action on your turn, you may alter a brewed spell you hold, transforming it into another spell. Choose one of your brewed spells and note its level. Then choose another alchemist spell you know of the noted level or lower. The chosen brewed spell now contains the second chosen spell, brewed at the noted level.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, regaining all expended uses whenever you complete a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="{{proficiency}}/Long Rest" action="Bonus Action">
			<description>You may alter a brewed spell you hold, transforming it into another spell. Choose one of your brewed spells and note its level. Then choose another alchemist spell you know of the noted level or lower. The chosen brewed spell now contains the second chosen spell, brewed at the noted level.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Chaotic Defense" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MIXOLOGIST_CHAOTIC_DEFENSE">
		<description>
			<p>You may harness the chaotic energy released by your mystery mixes to enhance your defense. Whenever you use a mixture brewed as a part of your Mystery Mix feature, roll a d4, a d6, a d8, a d10, and a d12, then add the numbers rolled together. You gain temporary hit points equal to the result, which last until the end of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Whenever you use a mixture brewed as a part of your Mystery Mix feature, roll a d4, a d6, a d8, a d10, and a d12, then add the numbers rolled together. You gain temporary hit points equal to the result, which last until the end of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Master Mixologist" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MIXOLOGIST_MASTER_MIXOLOGIST">
		<description>
			<p>You can combine disparate potion effects, fusing them together with masterful alchemy into a spell of unimaginable power. Whenever you utilize one of your brewed spells, you may choose another of your brewed spells. The chosen brew is masterfully mixed with the utilized brewed spell, expending the chosen potion. The utilized spell’s level is increased by an amount equal to the level of the expended brewed spell, up to a maximum of 9th level.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Whenever you utilize one of your brewed spells, you may choose another of your brewed spells. The chosen brew is masterfully mixed with the utilized brewed spell, expending the chosen potion. The utilized spell’s level is increased by an amount equal to the level of the expended brewed spell, up to a maximum of 9th level.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Mysterious Blob" type="Information" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_STATBLOCK_MYSTERIOUS_BLOB">
		<description>
			<p style="margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Tiny Ooze, Unaligned</em></p>
			<h4 style="margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 8 + PB</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> equal to three times the spell level</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 20 ft., climb 20 ft.</li>
			</ul>
			<table style="text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>4 (-3)</td><td>9 (-1)</td><td>14 (+2)</td><td>1 (-5)</td><td>6 (-2)</td><td>1 (-5)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Damage Resistances</strong> acid, bludgeoning, piercing, slashing</li>
				<li><strong>Condition Immunities</strong> blinded, charmed, deafened, exhaustion, frightened, prone</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> blindsight 30 ft. (blind beyond this radius), passive Perception 8</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> understands the languages of its creator but can't speak</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> —</li>
				<li><strong>Proficiency Bonus (PB)</strong> equals your bonus</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style="margin-top:5px; margin-bottom:10px" />
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Amorphous.</strong> The blob can move through a space as narrow as 1 inch wide without squeezing.</li>
				<li><strong>Spider Climb.</strong> The blob can climb difficult surfaces, including upside down on ceilings, without needing to make an ability check.</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style="margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Pseudopod.</strong> <em>Melee Weapon Attack:</em> your spell attack modifier to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. <em>Hit:</em> PB acid damage.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
	</element>

<!-- Pursuit of Necrosis -->
	<element name="Pursuit of Necrosis" type="Archetype" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_ALCHEMIST_PURSUIT_OF_NECROSIS">
		<supports>Alchemical Pursuit</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Alchemists are always trying to concoct perfection, but those of the Pursuit of Necrosis seek the perfect means of destruction. They craft deadly poisons and searing acids that can be imbued into any blade that invites them.</p>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NECROSIS_PURSUIT_SPELLS" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NECROSIS_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NECROSIS_SPELL_VENOM" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NECROSIS_TRUTH_OF_NECROSIS" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NECROSIS_HEART_OF_DESTRUCTION" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NECROSIS_GRIM_NATURE" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NECROSIS_NECROTIZING_RETALIATION" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>Those of the Pursuit of Necrosis seek the perfect means of destruction.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NECROSIS_PURSUIT_SPELLS" level="2" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NECROSIS_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="2" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NECROSIS_SPELL_VENOM" level="2" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NECROSIS_TRUTH_OF_NECROSIS" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NECROSIS_HEART_OF_DESTRUCTION" level="10" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NECROSIS_GRIM_NATURE" level="14" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NECROSIS_NECROTIZING_RETALIATION" level="18" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Pursuit Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NECROSIS_PURSUIT_SPELLS">
		<description>
			<p>You gain pursuit spells at the alchemist levels listed.</p>
			<h5>Necrosis Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Alchemist Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>germ, inflict wounds</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>melanosis, Melf ’s acid arrow</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><i>miasma, stinking cloud</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><i>produce poison, vitriolic sphere</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><i>alkahest, cloudkill</i></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_SPELL_GERM" level="2" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INFLICT_WOUNDS" level="2" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_SPELL_MELANOSIS" level="3" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MELFS_ACID_ARROW" level="3" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_SPELL_MIASMA" level="5" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STINKING_CLOUD" level="5" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_SPELL_PRODUCE_POISON" level="7" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_VITRIOLIC_SPHERE" level="7" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_SPELL_ALKAHEST" level="9" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLOUDKILL" level="9" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NECROSIS_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency with poisoner’s kits and martial weapons.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_POISONERS_KIT" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Spell Venom" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NECROSIS_SPELL_VENOM">
		<description>
			<p>You can imbue your weapons with the magic of your brewed spells like poison to a blade. As a bonus action on your turn, you may coat a melee weapon or a single piece of ammunition you touch with one of your brewed spells, which expends the brewed spell. You may only imbue a brewed spell with a casting time of 1 action and which does not have a range of self.</p>
			<p class="indent">The next time an attack is made with the imbued weapon in the next hour, the spell is delivered as a part of the attack, centered on the target. If the spell requires an attack roll, you make no spell attack roll, and if the weapon attack hits the target, the spell attack hits automatically. If the spell affects an area, the spell takes effect at the target point of origin on a hit or a miss.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, after which you can’t do so again until you complete a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="{{proficiency}}/Long Rest" action="Bonus Action">
			<description>You may coat a melee weapon or a single piece of ammunition you touch with one of your brewed spells, which expends the brewed spell. You may only imbue a brewed spell with a casting time of 1 action and which does not have a range of self.&#13;
			The next time an attack is made with the imbued weapon in the next hour, the spell is delivered as a part of the attack, centered on the target. If the spell requires an attack roll, you make no spell attack roll, and if the weapon attack hits the target, the spell attack hits automatically. If the spell affects an area, the spell takes effect at the target point of origin on a hit or a miss.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Truth of Necrosis" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NECROSIS_TRUTH_OF_NECROSIS">
		<description>
			<p>Your ability to implant your brewed spells into your weapons and utilize them as a serpent does its venom is greatly improved. You regain all expended uses of your Spell Venom feature whenever you finish a short or long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, your brewed spells and alchemist features ignore resistance to acid, necrotic, and poison damage and immunity to the poisoned condition, while also treating immunity to acid, necrotic, and poison damage as if it were resistance.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You regain all expended uses of your Spell Venom feature whenever you finish a short or long rest.&#13;
			Additionally, your brewed spells and alchemist features ignore resistance to acid, necrotic, and poison damage and immunity to the poisoned condition, while also treating immunity to acid, necrotic, and poison damage as if it were resistance.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Heart of Destruction" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NECROSIS_HEART_OF_DESTRUCTION">
		<description>
			<p>The vast array of venoms you have tested have empowered your body immensely. You gain immunity to poison.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, your weapon attacks deal an extra 1d6 necrotic damage on a hit.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your weapon attacks deal an extra 1d6 necrotic damage on a hit.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_POISON" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Grim Nature" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NECROSIS_GRIM_NATURE">
		<description>
			<p>Your ability to imbue your weapons with your potions is second nature to you. At the start of each of your turns, as long as you can take actions, you can immediately use your Spell Venom feature (no action required). When you use your Spell Venom in this way, you can’t do so as a bonus action this turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>At the start of each of your turns, as long as you can take actions, you can immediately use your Spell Venom feature (no action required). When you use your Spell Venom in this way, you can’t do so as a bonus action this turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Necrotizing Retaliation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NECROSIS_NECROTIZING_RETALIATION">
		<description>
			<p>You have imbibed in the essence of necrosis so heavily that it courses throughout your entire body. Whenever a creature within 30 feet deals damage to you, you may retaliate with vengeful poison. The target must make a Constitution saving throw against your alchemist spell save DC. On a failure, the target takes necrotic damage equal to your alchemist level and becomes poisoned until the start of your next turn. On a success, a creature instead takes half damage and is not poisoned.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Whenever a creature within 30 feet deals damage to you, you may retaliate with vengeful poison. The target must make a DC {{alchemist:spellcasting:dc}} Constitution saving throw. On a failure, the target takes {{level:alchemist}} necrotic damage and becomes poisoned until the start of your next turn. On a success, a creature instead takes half damage and is not poisoned.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

<!-- Pursuit of the Transmuter -->
	<element name="Pursuit of the Transmuter" type="Archetype" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_ALCHEMIST_PURSUIT_OF_THE_TRANSMUTER">
		<supports>Alchemical Pursuit</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The material world is as malleable as any potion, all it takes is the right touch. Alchemists who follow the Pursuit of the Transmuter have such a touch, bending the world and its shapes to their whim with notable ease.</p>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSMUTER_PURSUIT_SPELLS" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSMUTER_TRANSMUTERS_FIELD" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSMUTER_MUTABLE_FORMS" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSMUTER_TRANSMUTERS_INFLUENCE" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSMUTER_SUBLIME_CONTROL" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSMUTER_UNIVERSAL_MASTERY" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>Alchemists who follow the Pursuit of the Transmuter have such a touch, bending the world and its shapes to their whim with notable ease.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSMUTER_PURSUIT_SPELLS" level="2" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSMUTER_TRANSMUTERS_FIELD" level="2" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSMUTER_MUTABLE_FORMS" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSMUTER_TRANSMUTERS_INFLUENCE" level="10" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSMUTER_SUBLIME_CONTROL" level="14" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSMUTER_UNIVERSAL_MASTERY" level="18" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Pursuit Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSMUTER_PURSUIT_SPELLS">
		<description>
			<p>You gain pursuit spells at the alchemist levels listed.</p>
			<h5>Transmuter Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Alchemist Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>earth tremor, fog cloud</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>Maximilian’s earthen grasp, spike growth</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><i>erupting earth, transmute material</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><i>control water, stone shape</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><i>control winds, transmute rock</i></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_EARTH_TREMOR" level="2" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FOG_CLOUD" level="2" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MAXIMILIANS_EARTHEN_GRASP" level="3" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIKE_GROWTH" level="3" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ERUPTING_EARTH" level="5" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_SPELL_TRANSMUTE_MATERIAL" level="5" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTROL_WATER" level="7" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STONE_SHAPE" level="7" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CONTROL_WINDS" level="9" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_TRANSMUTE_ROCK" level="9" spellcasting="Alchemist" prepared="true" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Transmuter’s Field" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSMUTER_TRANSMUTERS_FIELD">
		<description>
			<p>You can blend the alchemical elements of the world around you, shaping it to your desire. You emit a field of alchemical influence in a 30-foot radius around you. As a bonus action on your turn, you may invoke one of the following effects:</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Advance Terrain.</b> You point to a 5-foot space on the ground that you can see within range. The chosen ground expands to fill an adjacent 5-foot space. Any creature caught in the space the ground fills is pushed 5 feet in a direction it chooses. After 10 minutes, affected terrain harmlessly returns to its original state.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Inhibit Movement.</b> You warp the terrain in a 5-foot radius sphere centered on a point you can see within range. The ground in the spell’s area becomes difficult terrain. After 10 minutes, affected terrain harmlessly returns to its original state.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Recess Terrain.</b> You point to a 5-foot cube space on the ground that you can see within range. The ground recesses 5 feet in a direction you choose. Any creature standing atop the recessed terrain can move harmlessly with the recessed terrain if it chooses. After 10 minutes, affected terrain harmlessly returns to its original state.</p>
			<p class="indent">You may use this feature a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, regaining all expended uses whenever you complete a short or long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="{{proficiency}}/Short Rest" action="Bonus Action">
			<description>You emit a field of alchemical influence in a 30-foot radius around you. As a bonus action on your turn, you may invoke one of the following effects:&#13;
			• Advance Terrain. You point to a 5-foot space on the ground that you can see within range. The chosen ground expands to fill an adjacent 5-foot space. Any creature caught in the space the ground fills is pushed 5 feet in a direction it chooses. After 10 minutes, affected terrain harmlessly returns to its original state.&#13;
			• Inhibit Movement. You warp the terrain in a 5-foot radius sphere centered on a point you can see within range. The ground in the spell’s area becomes difficult terrain. After 10 minutes, affected terrain harmlessly returns to its original state.&#13;
			• Recess Terrain. You point to a 5-foot cube space on the ground that you can see within range. The ground recesses 5 feet in a direction you choose. Any creature standing atop the recessed terrain can move harmlessly with the recessed terrain if it chooses. After 10 minutes, affected terrain harmlessly returns to its original state.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Mutable Forms" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSMUTER_MUTABLE_FORMS">
		<description>
			<p>You can more readily alter the states and material composition of objects around you. You gain the following additional options for your Transmuter’s Field feature:</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Grasping Earth.</b> You point to a 5-foot space on the ground within range, making a small, invisible sinkhole that fills a 5-foot space and lasts for 1 hour. The next time a creature enters the area, it must succeed on a Strength saving throw against your alchemist spell save DC or be restrained by the earth. A creature can use its action on its turn to remake the saving throw, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Proximity Combustion.</b> You point to a 5-foot space on the ground that you can see within range, formulating harmless, invisible chemicals on the ground which lasts for 1 hour. The next time a creature enters the area, the chemicals react and violently explode. Each creature within a 10-foot radius of the chosen space must make a Dexterity saving throw against your alchemist spell save DC. On a failure, a creature takes damage equal to your alchemist level, or half as much on a success. The type of damage is either: acid, fire, or poison (you choose when you first use this feature).</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You gain the following additional options for your Transmuter’s Field feature:&#13;
			• Grasping Earth. You point to a 5-foot space on the ground within range, making a small, invisible sinkhole that fills a 5-foot space and lasts for 1 hour. The next time a creature enters the area, it must succeed on a DC {{alchemist:spellcasting:dc}} Strength saving throw or be restrained by the earth. A creature can use its action on its turn to remake the saving throw, ending the effect on itself on a success.&#13;
			• Proximity Combustion. You point to a 5-foot space on the ground that you can see within range, formulating harmless, invisible chemicals on the ground which lasts for 1 hour. The next time a creature enters the area, the chemicals react and violently explode. Each creature within a 10-foot radius of the chosen space must make a DC {{alchemist:spellcasting:dc}} Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, a creature takes {{level:alchemist}} damage, or half as much on a success. The type of damage is either: acid, fire, or poison (you choose when you first use this feature).</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Transmuter’s Influence" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSMUTER_TRANSMUTERS_INFLUENCE">
		<description>
			<p>Your influence over the world around you grows in size and strength. Your Transmuter’s Field extends in a 60-foot radius around you.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>Your Transmuter’s Field extends in a 60-foot radius around you.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Sublime Control" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSMUTER_SUBLIME_CONTROL">
		<description>
			<p>You can formulate complex alchemical compounds in the ground around you. Whenever you expend a use of your Transmuter’s Field feature, you may choose two effects to invoke at once rather than one, without expending additional uses of the feature.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Whenever you expend a use of your Transmuter’s Field feature, you may choose two effects to invoke at once rather than one, without expending additional uses of the feature.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Universal Mastery" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSMUTER_UNIVERSAL_MASTERY">
		<description>
			<p>You have almost perfect control over the environment around you. Each of your Transmuter’s Field options improves in the following ways:</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Advance Terrain.</b> You may have the chosen space expand to fill a second 5-foot space. This second space must either be adjacent to the target space or the first expanded space.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Grasping Earth.</b> A target that fails its saving throw is also knocked prone.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Inhibit Movement.</b> The target area is a sphere with a radius up to 20 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Proximity Combustion.</b> A target that fails its saving throw takes damage equal to your proficiency bonus at the start of each of its turns for 1 minute. The target can then repeat its saving throw, ending the effect on itself on a success. The damage type is the same as the initially chosen type.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Recess Terrain.</b> The chosen point on the ground recesses up to 10 feet in the chosen direction.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Each of your Transmuter’s Field options improves in the following ways:&#13;
			• Advance Terrain. You may have the chosen space expand to fill a second 5-foot space. This second space must either be adjacent to the target space or the first expanded space.&#13;
			• Grasping Earth. A target that fails its saving throw is also knocked prone.&#13;
			• Inhibit Movement. The target area is a sphere with a radius up to 20 feet.&#13;
			• Proximity Combustion. A target that fails its saving throw takes {{proficiency}} damage at the start of each of its turns for 1 minute. The target can then repeat its saving throw, ending the effect on itself on a success. The damage type is the same as the initially chosen type.&#13;
			• Recess Terrain. The chosen point on the ground recesses up to 10 feet in the chosen direction.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

    <!-- Cantrips (0-Level) -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ACID_SPLASH">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_SPELL_BOOMING_BLADE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHILL_TOUCH">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CREATE_BONFIRE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIRE_BOLT">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_FROSTBITE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_SPELL_GREENFLAME_BLADE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHT">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MENDING">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POISON_SPRAY">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRESTIDIGITATION">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_FROST">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RESISTANCE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPARE_THE_DYING">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_THUNDERCLAP">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <!-- 1st Level -->
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ABSORB_ELEMENTS">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMAL_FRIENDSHIP">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BURNING_HANDS">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CAUSE_FEAR">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHARM_PERSON">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CHAOS_BOLT">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COLOR_SPRAY">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATE_OR_DESTROY_WATER">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CURE_WOUNDS">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_POISON_AND_DISEASE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_EXPEDITIOUS_RETREAT">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FAERIE_FIRE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FALSE_LIFE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEATHER_FALL">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FOG_CLOUD">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREASE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUIDING_BOLT">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEROISM">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ICE_KNIFE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ILLUSORY_SCRIPT">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INFLICT_WOUNDS">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_JUMP">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LONGSTRIDER">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_EVIL_AND_GOOD">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PURIFY_FOOD_AND_DRINK">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_SICKNESS">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SANCTUARY">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLEEP">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_ANIMALS">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_SPELL_TASHAS_CAUSTIC_BREW">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TASHAS_HIDEOUS_LAUGHTER">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THUNDERWAVE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <!-- 2nd Level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AID">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALTER_SELF">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINDNESS_DEAFNESS">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLUR">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CALM_EMOTIONS">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTINUAL_FLAME">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CROWN_OF_MADNESS">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKNESS">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKVISION">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_DRAGONS_BREATH">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_EARTHBIND">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENHANCE_ABILITY">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENLARGE_REDUCE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_TRAPS">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAME_BLADE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GENTLE_REPOSE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEAT_METAL">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_PERSON">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INVISIBILITY">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LESSER_RESTORATION">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEVITATE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_WEAPON">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MELFS_ACID_ARROW">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_FTOD_SPELL_NATHAIRS_MISCHIEF">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PASS_WITHOUT_TRACE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_FORCE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_POISON">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_ENFEEBLEMENT">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_FTOD_SPELL_RIMES_BINDING_ICE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCORCHING_RAY">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEE_INVISIBILITY">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHATTER">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SILENCE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIDER_CLIMB">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIKE_GROWTH">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WEB">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_SCOC_SPELL_WITHER_AND_BLOOM">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ZONE_OF_TRUTH">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <!-- 3rd Level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMATE_DEAD">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BESTOW_CURSE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINK">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLAIRVOYANCE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATE_FOOD_AND_WATER">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DAYLIGHT">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_MAGIC">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_WEAPON">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ENEMIES_ABOUND">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEAR">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEIGN_DEATH">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIREBALL">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_FLAME_ARROWS">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLY">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GASEOUS_FORM">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HASTE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HYPNOTIC_PATTERN">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_SPELL_INTELLECT_FORTRESS">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_LIFE_TRANSFERENCE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHTNING_BOLT">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_CIRCLE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_NONDETECTION">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANT_GROWTH">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_ENERGY">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REVIVIFY">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLEET_STORM">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLOW">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_DEAD">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STINKING_CLOUD">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TONGUES">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WATER_BREATHING">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WATER_WALK">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WIND_WALL">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <!-- 4th Level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHMENT">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLIGHT">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CHARM_MONSTER">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONFUSION">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_BANE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_EVARDS_BLACK_TENTACLES">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIRE_SHIELD">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FREEDOM_OF_MOVEMENT">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GIANT_INSECT">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_INVISIBILITY">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HALLUCINATORY_TERRAIN">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ICE_STORM">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POLYMORPH">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SICKENING_RADIANCE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_VITRIOLIC_SPHERE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_FIRE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_WATERY_SPHERE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <!-- 5th Level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AWAKEN">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLOUDKILL">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONE_OF_COLD">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTAGION">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_DANSE_MACABRE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_PERSON">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DREAM">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GEAS">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_RESTORATION">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_MONSTER">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_IMMOLATION">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INSECT_PLAGUE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_CURE_WOUNDS">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MODIFY_MEMORY">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PASSWALL">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAISE_DEAD">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RARYS_TELEPATHIC_BOND">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEEMING">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SKILL_EMPOWERMENT">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEPORTATION_CIRCLE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_TRANSMUTE_ROCK">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_WALL_OF_LIGHT">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <!-- 6th Level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHAIN_LIGHTNING">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CIRCLE_OF_DEATH">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATE_UNDEAD">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISINTEGRATE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLESH_TO_STONE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HARM">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEAL">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_FLAME">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_ICE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_STONE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_WIND">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MENTAL_PRISON">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_OTILUKES_FREEZING_SPHERE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_OTTOS_IRRESISTIBLE_DANCE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_PRIMORDIAL_WARD">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_TENSERS_TRANSFORMATION">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TRUE_SEEING">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_ICE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_THORNS">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <!-- 7th Level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DELAYED_BLAST_FIREBALL">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_FTOD_SPELL_DRACONIC_TRANSFORMATION">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ETHEREALNESS">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FINGER_OF_DEATH">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIRE_STORM">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIRAGE_ARCANE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_POWER_WORD_PAIN">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRISMATIC_SPRAY">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REGENERATE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RESURRECTION">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REVERSE_GRAVITY">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SIMULACRUM">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <!-- 8th Level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANTIMAGIC_FIELD">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLONE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_MONSTER">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEEBLEMIND">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GLIBNESS">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INCENDIARY_CLOUD">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MADDENING_DARKNESS">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIND_BLANK">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POWER_WORD_STUN">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <!-- 9th Level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FORESIGHT">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INVULNERABILITY">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POWER_WORD_HEAL">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POWER_WORD_KILL">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRISMATIC_WALL">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHAPECHANGE">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TIME_STOP">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TRUE_POLYMORPH">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TRUE_RESURRECTION">
    <supports>Alchemist</supports>
    </append>
</elements>
