<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Rogue - Blade Spinner</name>
		<source>Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything</source>
		<update version="0.1.0">
			<file name="rogue-blade-spinner.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Julitutu/Drizzts-Travelogue-of-Everything/refs/heads/main/Classes/rogue-blade-spinner.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Blade Spinner" type="Archetype" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_BLADE_SPINNER">
		<supports>Roguish Archetype</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Beauty and elegance, like steel wrapped in silk, the blade spinner delivers death to their foes as they move with equal parts poise and passion. The art of the blade spinner is that of a spinning whirlwind of brandished blades. Cutting this way and that—sometimes the same target twice and sometimes dispatching a duo of foes simultaneously—the blade spinner dances through the battlefield. Rarely one to shy away from a fight, the blade spinner wades into a battle like a fisher might ford a stream to find the perfect fishing hole.</p>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BLADE_SPINNER_FIGHTING_STYLE" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BLADE_SPINNER_CALCULATED_RISK" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BLADE_SPINNER_BLADE_DANCER" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BLADE_SPINNER_WHIRLING_DEATH" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BLADE_SPINNER_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BLADE_SPINNER_IMPROVED_WHIRLING_DEATH" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>The art of the blade spinner is that of a spinning whirlwind of brandished blades.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BLADE_SPINNER_FIGHTING_STYLE" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BLADE_SPINNER_CALCULATED_RISK" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BLADE_SPINNER_BLADE_DANCER" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BLADE_SPINNER_WHIRLING_DEATH" level="9" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BLADE_SPINNER_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="13" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BLADE_SPINNER_IMPROVED_WHIRLING_DEATH" level="17" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Fighting Style" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BLADE_SPINNER_FIGHTING_STYLE">
		<description>
			<p>Beginning at 3rd level, you adopt a particular style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following options. You can’t take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Blind Fighting.</b> You have blindsight with a range of 10 feet. Within that range, you can effectively see anything that isn’t behind total cover, even if you’re blinded or in darkness. Moreover, you can see an invisible creature within that range, unless the creature successfully hides from you.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Superior Technique.</b> You learn one maneuver of your choice from among those available to the Battle Master archetype. If a maneuver you use requires your target to make a saving throw to resist the maneuver’s effects, the saving throw DC equals 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Strength or Dexterity modifier (your choice.) You gain one superiority die, which is a d6 (this die is added to any superiority dice you have from another source). This die is used to fuel your maneuvers. A superiority die is expended when you use it. You regain your expended superiority dice when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Thrown Weapon Fighting.</b> You can draw a weapon that has the thrown property as part of the attack you make with the weapon. In addition, when you hit with a ranged attack using a thrown weapon, you gain a +2 bonus to the damage roll.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Two-Weapon Fighting.</b> When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second attack.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Fighting Style (Blade Spinner)" supports="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_BLIND_FIGHTING|ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_SUPERIOR_TECHNIQUE|ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_THROWN_WEAPON_FIGHTING|ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_TWOWEAPON_FIGHTING" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Calculated Risk" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BLADE_SPINNER_CALCULATED_RISK">
		<description>
			<p>At 3rd level, you have learned to efficiently engage your enemies without committing everything to a single attack. When you hit an enemy and are able to add your sneak attack damage, you can choose to not use all of the sneak attack dice on your damage roll. If you choose to do so, if you hit an enemy later in the same turn you can use the unspent sneak attack dice.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you hit an enemy and are able to add your sneak attack damage, you can choose to not use all of the sneak attack dice on your damage roll. If you choose to do so, if you hit an enemy later in the same turn you can use the unspent sneak attack dice.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Blade Dancer" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BLADE_SPINNER_BLADE_DANCER">
		<description>
			<p>At 3rd level, your practice and experience with your fluid movement while fighting has given you the grace of a skilled dancer. When you make a Charisma (Performance) check to dance, you have advantage on the roll.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you make a Charisma (Performance) check to dance, you have advantage on the roll.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Whirling Death" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BLADE_SPINNER_WHIRLING_DEATH">
		<description>
			<p>At 9th level, the first time on your turn that you use Calculated Risk to reduce your sneak attack damage dice by at least 2d6, you add 1d6 damage to each damage roll that uses your sneak attack that turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The first time on your turn that you use Calculated Risk to reduce your sneak attack damage dice by at least 2d6, you add 1d6 damage to each damage roll that uses your sneak attack that turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Extra Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BLADE_SPINNER_EXTRA_ATTACK">
		<description>
			<p>Beginning at 13th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" bonus="extra attack" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Improved Whirling Death" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BLADE_SPINNER_IMPROVED_WHIRLING_DEATH">
		<description>
			<p>Beginning at 17th level, if you reduce your initial sneak attack dice by at least 4d6 when you use Whirling Death, you add 2d6 damage to each damage roll that uses your sneak attack on your turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>If you reduce your initial sneak attack dice by at least 4d6 when you use Whirling Death, you add 2d6 damage to each damage roll that uses your sneak attack on your turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
</elements>