<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Wizard - Study of Eyes</name>
		<source>Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything</source>
		<update version="0.1.0">
			<file name="wizard-study-of-eyes.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Julitutu/Drizzts-Travelogue-of-Everything/refs/heads/main/Classes/wizard-study-of-eyes.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Study of Eyes" type="Archetype" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_WIZARD_STUDY_OF_EYES">
		<supports>Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Beholders and their kin are very often the subject of research, especially their eyes, and the innate magical properties they possess. Wizards of the tradition of the Study of Eyes dedicate their research trying to understand their alien behaviors and replicating their magical eye rays.</p>
			<p class="indent">For a few of these wizards their research can become an obsession, which can portray itself in a couple of ways. Some become rather reclusive, others start to exhibit similar habits to that of their study, even further still some try to obtain eyestalks to graft onto themselves.</p>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STUDY_OF_EYES_EYE_RAYS" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STUDY_OF_EYES_EYE_TYRANTS_PARANOIA" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STUDY_OF_EYES_ENHANCED_EYESIGHT" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STUDY_OF_EYES_IMPROVED_EYE_RAYS" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STUDY_OF_EYES_FOCUSING_LENS" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>Wizards of the tradition of the Study of Eyes dedicate their research trying to understand their alien behaviors and replicating their magical eye rays.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STUDY_OF_EYES_EYE_RAYS" level="2" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STUDY_OF_EYES_EYE_TYRANTS_PARANOIA" level="2" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STUDY_OF_EYES_ENHANCED_EYESIGHT" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STUDY_OF_EYES_IMPROVED_EYE_RAYS" level="10" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STUDY_OF_EYES_FOCUSING_LENS" level="14" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Eye Rays" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STUDY_OF_EYES_EYE_RAYS">
		<description>
			<p>Your study of beholders has given you a way of replicating the eye rays they can produce. As a bonus action, you may expend a spell slot to create an eye ray. The level of the spell slot you expend decides the die you roll, starting at 1d4 for a 1st level spell slot, 1d6 for a 2nd level spell slot, 1d8 for a 3rd level spell slot, 1d10 for a 4th level spell slot, and 1d12 for a spell slot of 5th level or higher. You then roll on the Eye Ray table with that die to determine the ray you create. The ray has a level equal to that of the expended spell slot and becomes inscribed in your spellbook until you fire the eye ray, or until you take a short or long rest. You can only have one eye ray stored this way, rolling on the Eye Ray table a second time replaces the previous ray with the new ray.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use an action while you hold the spellbook in which the ray is inscribed to choose another creature or object you can see within 120 feet of you to be the target of your eye ray. Once you have fired the eye ray, it is removed from your spellbook and you can’t use it again until you roll it again on the Eye Ray table.</p>
			<p class="indent">For rays that require a saving throw, the DC equals your spell save DC.</p>
			<h5>Eye Ray</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Die Result</td><td>Eye Ray</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>Elemental Ray. Choose acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder. The selected target must make a Dexterity saving throw. Roll a number of d6s equal to two + the ray’s level. A creature takes damage of the chosen type equal to the result on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>Fear Ray. The targeted creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be frightened of you for 1 minute. The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>Pushing Ray. The targeted creature must succeed on a Strength saving throw or be pushed a number of feet away from you in a straight line equal to 10 + five times the ray’s level and have its speed halved until the start of your next turn. If the creature is pushed into a wall or similar barrier, it stops and takes 1d6 bludgeoning damage for every 10 feet it was pushed.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>Charm Ray. The target creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become charmed by you for 1 hour, or until you or an ally deals damage to it.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td>Shrink Ray. If the target is a creature, it must succeed on a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the target suffers the “reduce” effect of the enlarge/reduce spell for 1 minute, except the damage of its attacks is reduced by a number of d4s equal to half the ray’s level (minimum of 1d4). The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on a success. If the target is a Large or smaller nonmagical object, it is shrunken without a saving throw.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td>Dazing Ray. The target creature must succeed on a Charisma saving throw or become dazed for 1 minute. While the target is dazed, its speed is halved, and it has disadvantage on attack rolls. The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on a success.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>7</td><td>Devour Magic Ray. For each spell affecting the target, make an ability check using your spellcasting ability and add the level of the expended spell slot. The DC equals 10 + the spell’s level. On a successful check, the spell ends. If the target is a magic item, it also loses all magical properties until the start of your next turn.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>8</td><td>Enervation Ray. The targeted creature must make a Constitution saving throw. Roll a number of d8s equal to three + the ray’s level. A creature takes necrotic damage equal to the result on a failed save, or half as much on a successful one.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>9</td><td>Banishing Ray. The target creature must succeed on a Charisma saving throw or be banished to a harmless demiplane for 1 minute. While there, the target is incapacitated. The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on a success.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>10</td><td>Polymorph Ray. The targeted creature must succeed a Wisdom saving throw or be polymorphed into a Beast of your choice of challenge rating 1 or lower for 1 minute, as per the polymorph spell.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>11</td><td>Telekinetic Ray. If the target is a creature, it must succeed on a Strength saving throw or be moved up to 30 feet in any direction. A creature lifted upward is suspended in mid-air. It is restrained by the ray’s telekinetic grip until the start of your turn or until you are incapacitated. If the target is an object weighing 1,000 pounds or less that isn’t being worn or carried, it is moved up to 30 feet in any direction. You can exert fine control on objects with this ray, such as manipulating a simple tool or opening a door or a container.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>12</td><td>Disintegration Ray. If the target is a creature, it must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw. Roll a number of d10s equal to three + the ray’s level. On a failed save, the target takes force damage equal to the result. If this damage reduces the creature to 0 hit points, its body becomes a pile of fine gray dust. If the target is a Large or smaller nonmagical object or creation of magical force, it is disintegrated without a saving throw. If the target is a Huge or larger object or creation of magical force, this ray disintegrates a 10-foot cube of it.</td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action">
			<description>You may expend a spell slot to create an eye ray. The level of the spell slot you expend decides the die you roll, starting at 1d4 for a 1st level spell slot, 1d6 for a 2nd level spell slot, 1d8 for a 3rd level spell slot, 1d10 for a 4th level spell slot, and 1d12 for a spell slot of 5th level or higher. You then roll on the Eye Ray table with that die to determine the ray you create. The ray has a level equal to that of the expended spell slot and becomes inscribed in your spellbook until you fire the eye ray, or until you take a short or long rest. You can only have one eye ray stored this way, rolling on the Eye Ray table a second time replaces the previous ray with the new ray.&#13;
			You can use an action while you hold the spellbook in which the ray is inscribed to choose another creature or object you can see within 120 feet of you to be the target of your eye ray. Once you have fired the eye ray, it is removed from your spellbook and you can’t use it again until you roll it again on the Eye Ray table.&#13;
			For rays that require a saving throw, the DC equals {{wizard:spellcasting:dc}}.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Eye Tyrant’s Paranoia" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STUDY_OF_EYES_EYE_TYRANTS_PARANOIA">
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency in the Perception skill.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, when you cast the find familiar spell, you can choose one of the normal forms for your familiar, or you can choose a gazer.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you cast the find familiar spell, you can choose one of the normal forms for your familiar, or you can choose a gazer.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_FAMILIAR" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Enhanced Eyesight" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STUDY_OF_EYES_ENHANCED_EYESIGHT">
		<description>
			<p>You have darkvision out to a range of 120 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, you learn the clairvoyance spell. You can cast it without a material component needed for seeing. You can also cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>You learn the clairvoyance spell. You can cast it without a material component needed for seeing. You can also cast it once without a spell slot.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
			<stat name="darkvision:range" value="120" bonus="base" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLAIRVOYANCE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Improved Eye Rays" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STUDY_OF_EYES_IMPROVED_EYE_RAYS">
		<description>
			<p>You can store up to two eye rays in your spellbook at a time, instead of one, and whenever you use your action to fire a ray, if you have another one stored in your spellbook, you may fire the second ray at a different target within range as a part of the same action.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can store up to two eye rays in your spellbook at a time, instead of one, and whenever you use your action to fire a ray, if you have another one stored in your spellbook, you may fire the second ray at a different target within range as a part of the same action.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Focusing Lens" type="Archetype Feature" source="Drizzt’s Travelogue of Everything Vol.2" id="ID_WOTC_DTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STUDY_OF_EYES_FOCUSING_LENS">
		<description>
			<p>Whenever you roll on the Eye Ray Table, you can roll the die twice and choose which of the two rays to record. If you roll the same number on both dice, you can ignore the number and choose any ray from among the possible results of the die you rolled. For example, if you expend a 1st level spell slot and roll two 1s, you can choose any ray you could’ve rolled as a part of rolling a d4 (between 1 and 4).</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Whenever you roll on the Eye Ray Table, you can roll the die twice and choose which of the two rays to record. If you roll the same number on both dice, you can ignore the number and choose any ray from among the possible results of the die you rolled.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
</elements>